<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hey, it&#39;s Alex! on Hey, it&#39;s Alex!</title>
    <link>http://heyitsalex.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hey, it&#39;s Alex! on Hey, it&#39;s Alex!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Normality of Apocalypses</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-normality-of-apocalypses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/the-normality-of-apocalypses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We woke up yesterday morning with my excited son urging us to get outside to see the snow outside. We didn’t exactly jump out of bed since we could feel the temperature and know immediately that this &lt;em&gt;wasn’t snow&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, we believed him that something was up and that there was something snow-like outside. Her mother quickly hypothesized that he must have been looking at bone dust from working on a bone blade that I’d have neglected to clean up. I relectantly admitted this was a fair hypothesis since I had in fact neglected to clean up after myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more minutes of talking and slowly accepting it was time to get up, my wife went outside while I checked the news. I immediately saw the pictures of the fire in The Gorge and the news about the smoke and ash coming to Portland.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4334/36401764043_44caa7c5d5_k_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        Ash caught in a spider’s web
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Later that day, we saw a UPS driver wearing a face mask and the mailwoman wearing a bandana. This was an unusual scene and it felt a bit like an pre-apocalyptic moment. But since things remained somewhat functional, everyone was going with their default routine except with the addition of air filtering devices on their faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down, looking at the ash still falling and got thinking. Was this what the apocalypse would look like? A slow series of events we can accomodate to? I was reminded of how normative comparisons and seeing your neighbor’s behavior can affect one’s actions. In this case, the neighbors were going to work and sending their kids to school. It seemed like it wasn’t the time to stop and reconsider the best thing to do in that moment. This might indeed be something like an apocalypse but we’ve got enough layers of abstraction to not realize it and it’s making us blind to what’s almost at our doorsteps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;interlude&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I imagine a parallel universe where enough neighbors would walk outside looking at the ash falling. Maybe a few of us would be crying thinking of the wildlife running away from the fire, losing their habitat. Maybe we’d start talking about how that’s also good for the forest to get a fire once in a while. Maybe we’d think of how the poor forest management and practices were making this one bigger and more devastating than it could have been. I imagine a few of us saying “fuck it, I’m not going to work today” and we’d just stay there, on the street, grieving together. Watching the red sun and the ashes falling silently, maybe we’d slowly start wanting to be closer to those events instead of just projecting pictures taken online in our minds. One of the neighbors would offer his place on the coast that needs some work to make sure the dead limbs aren’t a fire hazard.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Today, the mailwoman was back to normal (no bandana). The delivery guys were showing their unobstructed faces again. It’s true that the ashes weren’t falling from the sky like they did the day prior. But the smoke and red sun were still very present. In the background, we could hear the news about hurricanes down in the South. Major events for the news but nothing preventing us to go on with our routines. Was everyone already used to the new normal?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4426/36401380603_98516091ab_h_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The temperature of the water just jumped a few degrees and the pace to a boil just increased but it seems like we might just get used to this. Thinking back on the very visual scenes of apocalypse from yesterday, I wonder if we’ve just been in this apocalypse from even before I was born and I just didn’t have any reference to see it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Coding and Anarchy</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/on-coding-and-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/on-coding-and-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As I start writing this, I’ve just received an email from corporate HR announcing results of a survey that “clearly indicate” that employees feel like the most important thing to improve is &lt;em&gt;career development&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.makeameme.org/created/i-just-threw.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I just threw up in my mouth a little&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;interlude&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;I look through the window to my right and I see a jay landing on the fence a few feet away. The jay doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem terribly concerned about her future development or at least, she doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be making plans about them.&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As this happens, I think back how, just a few days ago, I was clumsily requesting from my management to opt-out from being managed. The request came after a long and unstructured reflection culminated by pressure build-up that just had to be released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-context&#34;&gt;Some Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write code for a living. Oficially, that makes me a Software Engineer. I’d prefer just saying that I’m a coder. Even better, I want to say I write code for a good chunk of my day but I also do plenty of other things with my life and I’d like to not &lt;em&gt;define&lt;/em&gt; myself as a coder. I draw, I photograph, I write, I make the occasional basket or spoon, I go camping with my kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;interlude&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A few weeks ago, two squirrels were playing in the backyard trees, or maybe one was courting the other. They were running and jumping from branch to branch, from one tree to the other. Suddenly, one jumped and fell unexpectedly. The other one was obviously taken aback and stood still for a moment, seemingly wondering what to do and if his friend was well. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the fall was hurtful or not but it really seemed like those squirrels were having a natural good time.&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I was made the tech lead of the team I was on. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it and said I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to do it. My repulsion came from my allergy to meetings but I also didn’t like the idea of being distracted from what I do best to include tasks that I didn’t think I was terribly good at. In the spirit of making this liveable for me given my feelings of apprehension, I was spared some of the most boring aspects of the job. I still didn’t feel comfortable with the situation. After some time and a pretty dramatic series of events and discussions, I finally got out of being assigned the title of tech lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next 2 years, things were better. I had enough reputation to be given the autonomy to decide what I should be working on. I knew what needed to be done and how to do it so I just did. It felt pretty good. However, I still had to deal with discussions about the future of my career or what I should do to get to my next promotion. Every time, I made it clear that I didn’t care about getting promoted. In fact, I requested to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be considered for a promotion. In doing so, I really wanted to avoid changes in how people saw me and my responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, I recently got asked what’s the next thing I wanted to work on. The motivation wasn’t a bad one. Managers want to help their employees remain satisfied and interested in their work. Talking about their future is one way they think they can achieve that. However, for reasons I won’t get into, I didn’t really want to discuss “big initiatives” and my “future at the company”. Really, I just wanted to live day to day and continue picking up the next piece of work that I thought I could help with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which led me to this request to opt-out of being managed. After trying to just dodge the big questions, I eventually gave up on trying and just asked to skip regularly scheduled one on one manager/employee meetings. I requested specifically to be allowed to do what I’m best at and not be stressed out or pressured to think about bigger career evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-this-means&#34;&gt;What this Means&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For several years, I had been fighting with everything that represented formal rules/hierarchy/management and was naturally doing work, collaborating with peers and having a good time when feeling free to do so. I still often felt trapped by some processes and even more by the context of my employment but I still had the mild good fortune of being tolerated in this  self-attributed freedom to self-organize. And only after I formulated this request to “opt-out of being managed” did I realize that what I was really longing for was &lt;strong&gt;anarchy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, anarchy is simply that freedom to self-organize. You might be a lone anarchist but, as I&amp;rsquo;ve described previously, it works really well when collaborating with peers/friends/family/community or even random strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I didn’t like the label “Software Engineer” is that it seems to be a discipline encompassing many different facets of building software (architecture, design, mentoring, etc). For me, “software engineering” feels like we’re trying to pack-in a career progression and, as a result, a hierarchy. You can only be in charge of &amp;ldquo;architecture&amp;rdquo; if you&amp;rsquo;ve done a few years of being a Senior Software Engineer. While coding involves the same things (design, architecture, teaching peers), it also sounds more action-driven and &lt;em&gt;holistic&lt;/em&gt;. To code something, you have to do those other things as well. However, all of it would be done naturally without as much formality around it. In fact, it might often feel &lt;em&gt;so natural&lt;/em&gt; that is just seems like one big flow of necessary actions. Granted, my interpretation of the words is very subjective but I think that I might not be alone in this interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the definitions of the labels I just mentionned are very subjective and informed by personal experience (rather than literal definitions), I realized at some point that my understanding of &lt;em&gt;coder&lt;/em&gt; (or my definition of it) goes hand in hand with anarchism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;anarchy-and-software&#34;&gt;Anarchy and Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, my friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.petermichaelbauer.com&#34;&gt;Peter Michael Bauer&lt;/a&gt; used coders as an example of natural anarchists during one of his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rewildportland.com/rewilding-201/&#34;&gt;Rewilding 201&lt;/a&gt; classes: promoting freedom of information, open-source projects with decentralized control, collaboration with peers with no ultimate ownership. At the time, I thought that this was true on some level but I downplayed this based on my experience in the software industry which doesn&amp;rsquo;t, like all industries,  follow the same ideology. Some companies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; have tried to do this with some success but not always with a lot of intention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes me think that, if given the chance, anarchism could work really well. Accidental anarchism success stories (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; seem to exist because groups of people naturally worked this way, it gave great results and it was enjoyable. Of course, pressures from the capitalist market and desire for growth (rather than quality or sustainability) might have resulted in this system falling appart after some time or when reaching a size too big for self-organization. However, it seems telling that this is how a lot of people enjoy and get excited about working this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;labeling-caveats&#34;&gt;Labeling Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a fan of using labels. It creates a division that is often a blocker to empathy. However, I think it can be useful in expressing a set of ideas more quickly to move the conversation to the next level. I also realize that labels can oversimplify those ideas and even erode some of their original meaning which then becomes a recipe for misunderstandings. Additionally, appropriating the label “arnarchist” to describe myself in the context of a capitalist tech industry might be a disservice to real anarchists trying to push real change and I&amp;rsquo;d like to limit my use only to open up a discussion about general anarchy amongst peers who feel like they naturally tend towards this way of working or living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;broader-picture&#34;&gt;Broader Picture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be one of those coders. You might have just realized that you might be an anarchist in the context of how you work. If so, you should consider what this means in other facets of life. It’s easy to compartmentalize and go back to your routine accepting the rules and hierarchy built-in all that surrounds us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe stop and ask yourself what this could mean if you were to imagine a different world. Maybe a world where the civilized &amp;ldquo;normality&amp;rdquo; is gone and we&amp;rsquo;re free to live in collaboration with our friends and neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;interlude&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Vireo comes back with a roadkill deer. After making initial cuts to separate the legs, others join in to process the meat, bones, hide, organs. Some of it is set up to dry as jerky while the organs are shared amongst the group and eaten on the spot. Some do cooking while some work on using all of the animal for tools. No one is directing the whole operation. Some is done in silence while some is met with chatter on what would be the most useful option in this situation, for this group of people, at this very moment.&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to continue exploring further down that path, you might enjoy reading this somewhat dense but interesting &lt;a href=&#34;https://theanarchistlibrary.org/library/moxie-marlinspike-and-windy-hart-audio-anarchy-radio-an-anarchist-critique-of-democracy&#34;&gt;Anarchist Critique of Democracy&lt;/a&gt;. And then, if you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what a world free of the rules and oppressive system could look like, go read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/aw/d/0143118072/ref=mp_s_a_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1500095661&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;pi=AC_SX236_SY340_QL65&amp;amp;keywords=a+paradise+built+in+hell&amp;amp;dpPl=1&amp;amp;dpID=51d-nXEdFYL&amp;amp;ref=plSrch&#34;&gt;A Paradise Built in Hell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If paradise now arises in hell, it’s because in the suspension of the usual order and the failure of most systems, we are free to live and act another way.&lt;/p&gt;
 
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;footer&gt;Rebecca Solnit, A Paradise Built in Hell&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll see you around the campfire on the other side of the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Home</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/beyond-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/beyond-home/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://500px.com/photo/165946055/morning-sun-by-alexandre-normand&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/165946055/m%3D900/2f76e64f7f566065021c4843cb09b0dc&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For months or probably even years, the question of where home is has been a nagging one. As we were migrating from one place to the other, we often felt lost with unfamiliar people and places.  But at the same time, we were learning about ourselves and clarifying what we&amp;rsquo;d desire from a environment and what we&amp;rsquo;d like to contribute back. After reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Beyond-War-Invasive-Species-Permaculture/dp/160358563X&#34;&gt;Beyond the War on Invasive Species&lt;/a&gt;, I now have a feeling that this migration process was more &lt;em&gt;natural&lt;/em&gt; that we thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, the more time passes, the less any previous “home” qualifies as a native place for myself and my family. To this day, I can still say that I spent most of my life in Québec. And the place I’ve stayed the longest at is a small village Eastern of the province. But, looking back on the various stages of my life, it would be difficult to pretend that this small village is my native place. In some ways, it &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have been since some of the key elements I’m looking for &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; were found in that place (and might still be) but the circumstances weren’t right and I was not right for that place at the time. I had to find another environment in which to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, since then, I’ve migrated and, one could say, became an invader. In some of those places I’ve migrated to, I changed. In a few of those, I think I might also have brought some change around me (maybe). And, as I look back on those patterns, I see parallels with my experience and invasive species in constantly changing ecosystems. I&amp;rsquo;m just another creature trying to find a good place that works for me and maybe bring something positive back to that place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I do a less than great job at contributing back to the places I visit than most &amp;ldquo;invasive&amp;rdquo; plants but I find comfort in knowing that I’m not necessarily forever lost for finding myself in a new and non-native place. The quest for a home is not stopping but it could become more interesting. Thinking of other living beings that become welcome additions to local ecosystems (at least by livings not fighting the war on invasives), I could now imagine myself having a similar role in a place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it might very well be that this place doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be one of my previous addresses for me to feel like I belong there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Going Back</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/going-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/going-back/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://500px.com/photo/119557113/sun-tree-camaraderie-by-alexandre-normand&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/119557113/m%3D900/66249bfc1d37efcb5453dec9c6e3a968&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In challenging civilization, agriculture and technology, an objection, internal and/or external, almost inevitably pops up: we can’t &lt;em&gt;go back&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of smart people have pointed out that things change without a necessary progression or regression. Technology has made us think of change in terms of &lt;em&gt;progress&lt;/em&gt;, as a one way road to always improving products. In actuality, changes can reveal themselves as good or bad and they can appear good for a time and become bad with a different context and environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking of change instead of progress can make some ideas appear more reasonable. But if you still think that we can’t escape &lt;em&gt;progress&lt;/em&gt; and that we must find clever new technological solutions to the problems we continue to introduce, read this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the response to people who say you can&amp;rsquo;t go back&amp;hellip;well, what happens if you get to the cliff and you take one step forward&amp;hellip;or you make a 180° turn and then take one step forward? Which way are you going? Which way &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; progress?. &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like how this provides an easy visual for our current trajectory and highlights the necessity to take a step back and look around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, the most important critique of turning around revolves around the difficulty to feed the current human population. To this, I want to offer a quote from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Against-Grain-Agriculture-Hijacked-Civilization/dp/0865477132&#34;&gt;Against the Grain&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the human endeavor takes as its primary reason for being the feeding of however many people issue from the senseless acts of reproduction, then the human endeavor is pointless. &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should note that Richard Manning does not clearly suggest a solution but this idea rings true, even if it makes us feel uncomfortable. If we agree that our current ways have little point, it would appear relevant to really consider taking a 180 turn. Or maybe we could take a less than 180 degrees turn if we think that the cliff is far enough ahead of us. But it becomes very hard to deny the need for a new direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that new path, we might find that the population will normalize itself with less drama than if we just run off the cliff. We might rediscover meaning in our connection with the non technological world. We might find a point to life in acts of regeneration, repairs and grief. And we might do so even if our speed does not allow us to stop in time before we reach the cliff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how about taking this turn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Doug Tompkins, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.180south.com&#34;&gt;180° South&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;Richard Magging, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Against-Grain-Agriculture-Hijacked-Civilization/dp/0865477132&#34;&gt;Against the Grain&lt;/a&gt;, A Counteragriculture
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longing for Belonging</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/longing-for-belonging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/longing-for-belonging/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://500px.com/photo/131336963/frosted-stones-by-alexandre-normand&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/131336963/m%3D900/dffeafcaa64e60df7de6c06c32b204fa&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I define belonging as elements that you feel a gravitational force pulling you towards. Such elements include family, people, language, land, place, plants, animals and, even, work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever sedentaries have a better chance, but no guarantees, to find those elements coming together nicely in a single geographical location. But some people have felt a force pulling them away from their geographical home/land/family in a quest to find some of those missing elements. “World travelers”,as some call them, might have a hard time when the inevitable questioning arises: where do I belong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, that same craving for belonging might have driven, intentional or not, that desire to travel. And the travel/relocation offers a unique perspective and opportunity to discover things about oneself, connect dots and discover new ideas. But it also, paradoxically, requires giving up some of the elements that define a sense of belonging (namely: land, place, family and, sometimes, language).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That process has played an instrumental role in my discovery of some fundamental wrongs of our culture and some of the uncomfortable illusions we entertain in regards to the solutions for a good future. That process has accelerated my  discovery of what makes &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; and how I want to play a role in this connected world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, where do I belong? Who do I belong with? I don’t know. To complicate things further, the answer might be different for the members of my immediate family. As “world travelers”, we’re faced with the possibility that most logical option might involve choosing a compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe spending some more time searching and finding what constitutes the true essence of our belonging will expose new and fuller alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in the Moment or Not</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/in-the-moment-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/in-the-moment-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Living in the moment seems like a very serene way of living. A very buddhist perspective free from the worries of the past and the future. One path to happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I find it incredibly difficult to live in the moment. I guess my reasons are commonplace and typical which makes me a very average being. I find it difficult because I’m worried. It’s hard because I think about the future. It’s impossible because I think of what I should be doing rather than what I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also think there’s more to it. It’s possible that this is just my way of finding an excuse but I think that we might not have the luxury of living in the moment. We&amp;rsquo;re the privileged ones on top of this civilized world with no or very little conscience of the damage we&amp;rsquo;re inflicting on all living things. After having played the role of evil in this story for so long, can we really afford to live this moment? Maybe it would be a good idea &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; but I think the focus in this time of near collapse would be better served by reading the past and imagining a future of redemption and regeneration. I can&amp;rsquo;t be enjoying myself right now because this life and therefore this moment has been made possible by acts of destruction and disrespect for life. Living that moment would just go in support of this and it&amp;rsquo;s a hard choice to make when you&amp;rsquo;ve reached a certain level recognition for what is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live in pain and absent mindedness because I think of the terrible destruction started by my ancestors that I&amp;rsquo;m perpetuating implicitly by living this life. I stare at the emptiness thinking of a life I could be living in accordance to my views. Oh sure, I can occasionally distract myself for temporary relief but, more generally, I think it would be too easy to live comfortably in this moment sponsored by terrible destruction.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/131650409/m%3D900/33017a244c6a562f30ad55973cbd0532&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        Frozen Maple Leaf. This proved to be one of those distractions that, for a few minutes, provided relief from constantly thinking about the past or the future. I think.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Barrier of Isolation</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-barrier-of-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 09:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/the-barrier-of-isolation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are many barriers to rewilding but I’d like to tackle one today. I realize that my perspective is one of a priviledged white man but I can’t pretend it’s any other way and I just feel the need to share. Thanks for reading.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/119443369/m%3D900/fb6bda485505dc2a922d626fde2e1769&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        A Bite.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My family and I moved in 2012 on my quest to find meaning in my work (or, incidentally, my &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;). If we already suffered an isolated life before the move, it wasn’t worse than most priviledged modern families. Of course that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean much as our modern world pushes us further and further away from each other. Still, we had friends, family and we even talked to some of our neighbors (!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We lost some of that when we landed in California. As time passed, we did get to know some people: mostly me through work and Flavie through school. After 3 years, we moved to Portland because of my SF tech overdose, the ridiculousness of it all (alluding to the rent prices and the water shortage would barely scratch the surface) but also because there seemed to be a focus in Portland on things that that started coming in focus for ourselves: unschooling, rewilding, nature and health. But with remote work and unschooling, we again hit a bump on the isolation road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to what I really wanted to say: the more we move closer to our uncommon convictions, the more we might feel isolated. In other words, the more we move away from a system that we can’t support anymore, the harder it seems to become to stay connected with people that still fully support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, I think, is one significant barriers to rewilding for some. Or so it appears initially. While it’s easy to continue having casual conversations with colleagues and friends who don’t currently share the same views, it feels like a lie by ommission to avoid talking about rewilding. Because, truthfully, everything can be connected to the desire for civilization to collapse, for our place to be restored in nature, for our regenerative work to begin. But there are some people that would turn off completely if exposed to these ideas prematurely. And skipping on those discussions seems to me like just another form of isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But maybe it doesn’t have to be that way. Maybe it’s just a matter of choosing the right words. Most people, deep down, aren’t happy with their life and that opens up a discussion about &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; better. For a relative newcomer to the ideas of rewilding like me, it might even be easier to relate to people who are uninitiated rather than the teachers who are so further ahead. It might not be as satisfactory as getting to the core of &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; we should tackle everything that needs to be done but it seems like an important part. With the benefit that there’s a potential for reaching out to more people and even strenghtening relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All said, I believe the reality might be an unelegant mix. I can’t help but feel the need to break away from this isolation bubble by interacting with like-minded folks. It seems &lt;em&gt;somewhat&lt;/em&gt; realistic that some some form of rewilding discussions can happen with friends who are not currently thinking of rewilding or just not thinking of rewilding in the same terms and definitions. It seems unrealistic that this can be fully satisfactory. I’ve said it before but it seems as relevant today than when I wrote this &lt;a href=&#34;http://heyitsalex.net/new-light-on-that-blue&#34;&gt;long ago&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m not sure friends are forever but we forever needs friends.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, ideally, some of those friends would be passionate rewilders because it’s a topic that we can’t really pause from thinking about for very long.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive Optimism</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/positive-optimism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/positive-optimism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I felt lost when I wrote my &lt;a href=&#34;http://heyitsalex.net/negative-optimism&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; regarding the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holocene_extinction&#34;&gt;Holocene extinction&lt;/a&gt;. I thought I had just learned that our species had a destructive nature since its inception even &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seven_generation_sustainability&#34;&gt;within cultures focusing on sustainability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now think that I had misinterpreted my readings. Whether intentional or not, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Sixth-Extinction-Unnatural-History/dp/1250062187/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1446433599&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=The+Sixth+Extinction&#34;&gt;The Sixth Extinction&lt;/a&gt; implied with the retelling of conversations about the history of homo sapiens that destruction had followed the path of our species from our early beginnings. However, after some more researching, it appears that, while there were extinctions before civilization, those were not quite at the same level nor within the same context. I already had some intuition to that effect and I felt relief to find some of that evidence presented in &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/rewildandlive&#34;&gt;Rewild 101&lt;/a&gt;. Civilization would have amplified our destructive impact by orders of magnitude. However, I now think that extinctions prior to civilization were closer to events that would occur naturally as part of evolution and cohabitation between other species. We can &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; bad about those but they should reveal themselves as neither good or bad. In contract with current extinctions, those represent something closer to a natural outcome to a particular set of circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this new perspective doesn’t really change the idea that we should rewild and reconnect with nature, it does offer us an interesting proposition: we could have a positive place amongst other livings. That process might involve a lot of hardships and it won’t happen quickly but the idea that it could brings me joy here and now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negative Optimism</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/negative-optimism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/negative-optimism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a snapshot in a continuous exploration of the meaning of life and our place in nature. All thoughts and ideas expressed here are subject to change at any moment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas evolve and change. Or, at least, they usually do. When I picked up &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Sixth-Extinction-Unnatural-History/dp/0805092994&#34;&gt;The Sixth Extinction&lt;/a&gt;, I had a sense that I might not get much new to advance my current ideas. I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My skepticism seem warranted when, reading the introduction, it appeared as if the book was about the telling of a great story first and foremost. But while that might have been the author’s  initial motivation, she made a convincing case that even if she might have been looking for a story, it might just happen to be one that is incredibly captivating because of its importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sixth Extinction, also named the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holocene_extinction&#34;&gt;holocene extinction&lt;/a&gt;, is the one we&amp;rsquo;re currently experiencing. There are many intuitive ways we can imagine ourselves playing a role in extinctions that globally make this one up: climate change, GMOs, surpopulation, overfishing. All of which are fairly recent on a geologic time scale. Going back just a little bit further, we could think that agriculture, civilization and colonization could have been immensely destructive. That would also be very right. It was and it remains more so than anything else. As we go back further though, it gets increasingly interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; surprised to find more evidence that our hunter gatherers ancestors might also have been causing mass extinctions. What follows is based on very incomplete research is incomplete and only partial data. Also consider that we got facts about history wrong many times before. So, with the data that we currently have, it would seem like extinctions started with the homo sapiens. Before homo sapiens, neanderthals seemed to be doing well on Earth. It remains to be explored what was so different between neanderthals and homo sapiens but it would seem that ingenuity, creativity and ambition were qualities that could have had a major factor in newly occurring destruction. Or maybe it was our ability to tell ourselves stories, deal with virtual/abstract things (i.e. money, religion) and collaborate together based on those stories. Or maybe it was a deep and constant appetite for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colonizing remote continents is one obvious way homo sapiens have impacted ecosystems and caused harm. But it&amp;rsquo;s also very obvious how the same traits are still causing us to destroy faster and more decisively by the day. The same homo sapiens quality that is making me want to write about this idea is contributing to us to destroy our environment. This was a deep revelation for me, as a self-qualified &amp;ldquo;creative&amp;rdquo; person. What the planet would need, it seems, is boring and predictable species. Ones that are content living in equilibrium in their habitat. But this is fundamentally not how homo sapiens are. And very disappointingly, native tribes are not immune to this. It follows that rewilding ourselves might not be the saving grace. It &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; be going in the right direction: using less resources and being more connected to nature can only be good. It would most definitely be a better life for most of us urban folks. But I doubt it would be enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that this is a hard conclusion to come to and it might appear awfully negative. I guess it is. But only if we view it purely in the lens that &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt; means &lt;em&gt;human life&lt;/em&gt;. If we try to view human life as just another form of life, there’s optimism. Because, with the bringing of the Sixth Extinction, it&amp;rsquo;s likely that one of the species going extinct is going to be the homo sapiens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is that optimistic? Well, let’s talk about the common “optimistic” scenario for a constrast. One common suggested alternative is that the human &amp;ldquo;ingenuity&amp;rdquo; gives us a solution. Imagine technological means to explore and settle on a new planet. Throw the Earth away and take our &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt; to a new world. This, to me, is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; pessimistic scenario. After destroying all life on Earth, we&amp;rsquo;d get to do it all over on another world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now what? I&amp;rsquo;m going to bet that we don&amp;rsquo;t survive the Sixth Extinction. I&amp;rsquo;m going to bet that several resilient or lucky species do. I&amp;rsquo;m going to bet that with enough time, evolution will take its course and new species with pop up. The Earth will find a new balance again. Life will strive and the Earth will be a nice home again. Maybe a new species of bipeds like the Neanderthals will appear. A smart biped ape that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be inflicted by the urge to realize bigger dreams than just living in symbiosis with its environment. That, to me, is the optimistic scenario. That&amp;rsquo;s the one I&amp;rsquo;m betting on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that betting against my own species could be considered trahison. But if we just think of ourselves as one member of a larger group that is &amp;ldquo;life&amp;rdquo;, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem as terrible of an idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, how this affects how I live now gets a bit more complicated. We all want to live. &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; still want to live. I&amp;rsquo;d like to move in the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; direction but it becomes very confusing as to what this could be. Another way to look at it would be that as we&amp;rsquo;re going extinct, I should just find a quiet space to reflect in the meantime. A life closer to nature. Try to find solace knowing that when we won&amp;rsquo;t be there, some of this nature and some of this life will actually be able to strive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So maybe that&amp;rsquo;s it. It might be time to come to peace with the resolution that we screwed up. Come to terms with the idea that &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; are the problem. Saying our final good byes before we go the way of the dodo. And know, that maybe, probably, there will still be life after us and that life will be smart enough to not try and get too smart to disturb a fragile and beautiful equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, of course, this might also be a bump in the road to a brighter, continuously evolving set of thoughts and ideas where we’d be a force for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: Back to &lt;a href=&#34;http://heyitsalex.net/positive-optimism&#34;&gt;positive optimism&lt;/a&gt; with new information after digging into pre-history. Read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://heyitsalex.net/positive-optimism&#34;&gt;next post&lt;/a&gt; for my current thoughts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Big Illusions</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-big-illusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/the-big-illusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I closed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Big-Ratchet-Humanity-Thrives/dp/0465044972&#34;&gt;The Big Ratchet&lt;/a&gt; mad with rage. I wasn’t surprised to find myself in disagreement with the author but I did find myself unable to contain my emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While venting, I realized what frustrated me. The author goes into the history of humanity and its “ingenuity”. She goes on to tell the story of “pivots” in history. Along the way, tragedies happen (indigenous people are exterminated, species disappear and sustainable ways of life are destroyed) but they’re always brushed off very quickly as minor downsides of something that brought a net positive. Each time, she tells us that out of the problems that we introduced, we found solutions that made us better than when we started. And, in every case, I found myself offended that she would say that. In every case, I was thinking to myself that we had just taken a wrong turn that should have prompted us to turn back. Instead, we celebrated an illusion of progress that was bringing us deeper into a path of destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multiple times, she goes on to say that we were better because more people had food, we could expand and considering going back would be impossible because of all the life that needed to be sustained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But which life? The fact is that she equals “life” with &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; life. More precisely, the modern civilized human. What about all the life that we, empire people, ended up killing the process? What about the species that go extinct every day? She shows a profound denial of what life truly is. Life is everywhere and it relies on the balance we so obviously disturbed and now try to control. Would going back to hunting and gathering mean widespread famine? Likely. But would this be a net loss for life? I’m not so sure. All signs point to a potential for better balance. In the process, it would bring a long lost humility to our species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would also probably mean that I’d be one of the casualties given my dependence on modern drugs for my disease of modern life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to say what I would decide for humanity if I was asked to. Would I go for the continuity, hoping we’d find remedies to all of the ill we’re inflicting on our world and ourselves? Or would I go for turning back, knowing this would bring the demise of myself and countless others who exist or continue to exist with dependence on modernity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds like an easy decision. There’s hope that human ingenuity might bring us to unimaginable territories and there’s  no chance I could live without the modern civilization as a type 1 diabetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I am, in theory, in favour for turning back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the days, week or month of that life that I’d get back living connected to other life might be worth it. I’d hope that my fear of death would carry a lighter weight in the balance next to the possibility of life &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; the planet rather than as a farmer of its resources.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/alexnormand/10094389934/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5346/10094389934_79d4690006_o_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainties</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/uncertainties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 09:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/uncertainties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I know that I know nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a famous saying that resonates profoundly these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe in sudden triggering factors outside of our reflex for self-biography narration but I will surrender and say that 2013 was a markedly transformative year in my life. That’s when I radically changed my lifestyle to try and fix my degrading type 1 diabetic health. I had already learned about the effectiveness of simple behavioural science principles to power my commitment to make change happen.  I felt the benefits very quickly. In less than 6 months, I had started the reversal of early signs of retinopathy. But I had also learned that things weren’t so simple in nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 2013 was when I learned that I had trusted the wrong sources about nutrition and health more generally. What else did I assumed as universal truth but wasn’t? 18 months later, I’m still wondering what’s the best diet for me. I learned that there isn’t one solution that fits everyone. I’ve also learned about several things that affect health but, more importantly, I learned that it’s only a tiny fraction of what there is to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I also learned about rewilding. I then learned that rewilding means different things to different people. I learned some of its definitions. I learned about new ideas on waste, consumption and the economy religion. I learned about tiny housing and a minimalistic way of life. None of it is simple. There are some very compelling perspective on the modern life but there’s also no clear and unique solution and path forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m sitting here bombarded with very assertive statements and solutions to achieve health, accomplishment, happiness and financial freedom. But I also know things are complicated and personal. There’s rarely a single answer. There’s a lot of information to process and lots of questions to pounder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post isn’t about how to be creative, productive, healthy or happy. I wouldn’t know what to prescribe because it’s complicated. This post isn&amp;rsquo;t about how everything is fucked and there&amp;rsquo;s no solution. Even if that were true, we woulnd&amp;rsquo;t know until we try something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that I&amp;rsquo;m uncertain what this post is about. But maybe that&amp;rsquo;s what the theme. My search for my very own personal answers is full of uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while uncertainties that can be paralyzing, there&amp;rsquo;s one thing I do know and that it&amp;rsquo;s nice things usually happen when you try something different. If nothing more than ruling out an idea while prompting a fresh set of questions and opening up new paths to answers. Here&amp;rsquo;s to finding the next path.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://500px.com/photo/14092047/grass-and-bokeh-yeah-by-alexandre-normand&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/14092047/m%3D900/374628c29b6de4a859eb8bcdb6dbf069&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Beats Talking, Most of the Time</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/doing-beats-talking-most-of-the-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 10:53:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/doing-beats-talking-most-of-the-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I last posted. I have no excuses; I simply have a good reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was &lt;em&gt;too busy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on very exciting projects so that work consumed my time and energy enough that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to &lt;em&gt;talk&lt;/em&gt; about all what I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still working on the same exciting things. But wait! I&amp;rsquo;m still here aren&amp;rsquo;t I? I felt the need to come back and do something different (but still something &lt;em&gt;quick&lt;/em&gt;). So here is a completely free to use wallpaper with an appropriate quote from none other than myself. Or could it be possible that someone else said that before I did and I just don&amp;rsquo;t know? Nonsense!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure you all agree that this is priceless? That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m not putting a price on it. You are free to use, modify and pretty much do anything you&amp;rsquo;d like with this as long as you give me the credit and it fits under the terms of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported License &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick your version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexnormand/9380273987/&#34;&gt;My Alex special edit version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/gp/alexnormand/tk78YE&#34;&gt;Full size, with quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/gp/alexnormand/kQ53in&#34;&gt;Full size, no quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexnormand/9380273987/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3731/9380273987_17b307dd6a_o_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        Doing Beats Talking, Right?
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juxtapose</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/juxtapose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 05:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/juxtapose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I came across some stunning &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/a/wxBBm#0&#34;&gt;compositing work&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://realcalvinandhobbes.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;Michael Den Beste&lt;/a&gt;. The project juxtaposes drawings of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calvin_and_Hobbes&#34;&gt;Calvin and Hobbes&lt;/a&gt; with fitting nature photographs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By themselves, the photos would be pretty good albeit lacking a distinguishing element. With Calvin and Hobbes, the scene comes alive. The drawings bring a touch of imagination in an otherwise very real scene. I felt as if the world was being filled with mystical creatures from storybooks. It&amp;rsquo;s breaking the monotony of a thousand pretty pictures while celebrating of the beauty of nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can tell I felt inspired by that work. I also happen to take random unpublished pictures suited for such compositing work: &lt;em&gt;wallpaper-nice&lt;/em&gt; caliber but nothing crazy unique. I also happen to draw things. Or, I try to. Here is my first attempt at this type of composite art. It&amp;rsquo;s an old pouring rain picture that I augmented with my drawing of a snail. I have much better photos in reserve for this type of work but this one seemed to be fitting with my character so I&amp;rsquo;m going with that. Uncharacteristically for me, this won&amp;rsquo;t be a scheduled project. But, I&amp;rsquo;ll make more.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8234/8508412905_e34d5b1429_b.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        This is it.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;techdetails&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical details:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Original picture processed with Aperture, exported via Dropbox to iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I drew the a low-resolution version of the snail with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fiftythree.com/paper&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt; on the iPad and my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tenonedesign.com/connect.php&#34;&gt;Pogo Connect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Then, I exported to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.procreate.si/&#34;&gt;Procreate&lt;/a&gt; and used it as the basis for a higher resolution and full color version.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Composited the photo and drawing in Procreate.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;That output was then tweaked with snapseed for drama and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop-touch.html&#34;&gt;Photoshop Touch&lt;/a&gt; to add the horizontal black border.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter to Github</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/love-letter-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/love-letter-to-github/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure class=&#34;medium&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Octocalex-2012-12-16-07.49.31-168-PM1.png&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        I&amp;#39;m really sorry about this. I wanted an image and I thought drawing myself octocat-style would be cool. I guess it could have been if I had done a better job. For the record, I blame the tools. No SketchBook Ink for me next time.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have one thing I want to say today: I love &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this would just barely be worthy of a tiny tweet (and not even a _good_ one), I&amp;rsquo;m going to stretch this as far as I can to get to a blog post length. Just because I feel like blogging today. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s just how it&amp;rsquo;s going to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past week was really great. Don&amp;rsquo;t you care to know why? Well, fine, I&amp;rsquo;m telling anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with me just trying to get some data on the distribution of the data across regions in hbase. I thought it was something we should be looking at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enters &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sentric/hannibal&#34;&gt;Hannibal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a few minutes, I had cloned it, built it and had it running against one of our clusters. The visuals are really good and it definitely increases our ability to quickly see where we&amp;rsquo;re at compared to a text output (which can also be done pretty easily with an hbase shell script).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this running instance on our data quickly came the realization that we&amp;rsquo;d use this for real. And, like, &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On closer look, I noticed issues with getting compaction logs. Also, I started thinking of some things we might tweak to make it easier to have this deployed and running internally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into the details of the changes involved. The &lt;strong&gt;process&lt;/strong&gt; is really the topic I had in mind when sitting down to write this. Or rather the lack thereof really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you notice? I just lied straight to your face and I knew you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t budge. Actually, there _is_ a process but Github makes it all so easy and fun that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like the drag we so often associate with processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how this lays out: You read about this thing or google your way to it. You need this thing and someone already wrote it. It starts here and then&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clone, build, run and use the thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something missing or that could use some improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You feel the urge to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the critical part right there. It&amp;rsquo;s often where things &lt;em&gt;get complicated&lt;/em&gt;. You might need to file a ticket first with steps to reproduce. You might need to sell people of that feature you think _should definitely_ be in the scope of the project. You know, it&amp;rsquo;s complicated™. But Github helps. Let&amp;rsquo;s get on with how this goes with it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You fork it. A one click step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You do the work. And it&amp;rsquo;s the most fun part. You&amp;rsquo;re excited because this is something that bugged &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s something _you_ care about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Done with the changes? Now it&amp;rsquo;s pull requesta extravaganza! This is when you get to show off the interesting work you&amp;rsquo;ve cared so much about. Also, because it&amp;rsquo;s cool to work with people excited about your project, interesting discussions follow. Meeting new folks. You know, _talking_ (or, more accurately, &lt;em&gt;typing&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just describing one scenario here but let&amp;rsquo;s say everything is right and your changes were merged into the upstream repo. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this feel &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;? It&amp;rsquo;s almost silly but I just feel like a little boy and I want to show mommy how proud I am of the thing I just did. Even for a one line change. I&amp;rsquo;d like to show the whole world about this thing I just did. Please refrain though. People will run away screaming if you do this too often. And maybe even the first time you do it. So, please, don&amp;rsquo;t!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You just feel like smiling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, you can get the same great rewarding feeling from contributing to any open source project even if that&amp;rsquo;s not hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. But the entry barrier is just a little bit higher. It takes more time. Some of that precious and limited energy that you have is spent on the _other_ stuff that, well, isn&amp;rsquo;t as much fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything to make the process so easy it just seems to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; exist is an amazing feat. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; really enables tons of changes (okay, I just made that up but I really think it&amp;rsquo;s a good uneducated guess) by just making a path available from discovering a personal need to getting it done. Github is empowering people to fix it &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt;. And we all know how momentum is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I won&amp;rsquo;t shock anyone if I say we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to go back to a world without &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. More than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/&#34;&gt;JetBrains&lt;/a&gt;, Github really brings the _develop with pleasure_ motto to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Github, I love you. Never leave me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rdio Stole all the Music and Gave it to All of Us </title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/how-rdio-stole-all-the-music-and-gave-it-to-all-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/how-rdio-stole-all-the-music-and-gave-it-to-all-of-us/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/DSC_1031-1024x682.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        My old days of listening to music.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We&amp;rsquo;ve got all you music. Surrender a fee and it&amp;rsquo;s yours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds like a ransom note from a villain. It&amp;rsquo;s not. This is the promise of music services like &lt;a href=&#34;http://rdio.com/&#34;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spotify.com/&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember feeling hesitant when the digital age began. I liked putting my favourite albums on display. After some time, I realized that I never actually looked at them and it was just more _stuff_ to carry around. I slowly stopped buying physical CDs. This was liberating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the iTunes age. I would buy albums and store them in a nice folder that kept growing. Backed up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com/&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt; too. However, I now look at some of this music and I&amp;rsquo;ve either listened it to death or I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my mind about it. In all cases, most of the time, I just listen to the more recent great stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last part has been a problem for me in the last few years. You know how it is. When you become a dad, you&amp;rsquo;ve got less free time. I know some dads that are still up-to-date on the latest great music but I think you&amp;rsquo;ve got only a few picks to make when you&amp;rsquo;ve got less free time. I chose photography and software. I had to give up on music. Thankfully, some of the bands I was listening to are still doing some innovative work so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t  _completely _out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I moved this year, I also decided to try to get back into it a bit more. Ideally without having to put too much time into it. My priorities hadn&amp;rsquo;t changed. I tried &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spotify.com/&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pandora.com/&#34;&gt;Pandora&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have such a good experience with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spotify.com/&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;. Even though I had access to a huge selection, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to look for. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pandora.com/&#34;&gt;Pandora&lt;/a&gt; was definitely better in that regard. I could use something I knew as a reference and get a radio station with potentially good picks. That was unsatisfying to me though. When you stumble on a great track and want to listen to more of that band, you&amp;rsquo;re left on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;http://rdio.com/&#34;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt;. After reading good words about it, I decided give the trial a try. I liked it. I still do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I had access to playlists that were a great starting point (like pitchfork&amp;rsquo;s best songs). Then, as I discovered things I liked, I could add bands and albums to my collection and even synchronize them to my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s all I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy discovery with trusted curated content and access to an exhaustive music library. Sure, I have to pay every month. But, one month of &lt;a href=&#34;http://rdio.com/&#34;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt; is the price of a single album on iTunes. Yes, I lose it all if I decide to cancel. When you think about it though, that music I was listening to a few months ago isn&amp;rsquo;t really what I&amp;rsquo;m going to want to listen to in two months anyway. Also, if I were to find another solution, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have the same music there anyway. And if not, that&amp;rsquo;s fine too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really cool thing about all of this though goes beyond easy access to music: No more &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;. Nothing to carry around. This is definitely more liberating that the jump to the digital age. This is acknowledging that we change and we might not have to keep all of our things from the past with us because we cherished it at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have stuff I&amp;rsquo;m carrying along with me, way _too_ much. I know. Hopefully though, this stuff is now more of my own creations (or my creation tools) than stuff I acquire. Not ideal, but better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Still Remember, Even After 6 Months</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/i-still-remember-even-after-6-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 05:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/i-still-remember-even-after-6-months/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/JeMeSouviensVersion2Landscape-1024x522.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        I remember. Well, at least, what I haven&amp;#39;t forgotten.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: the initial version was way too purple on print. It did look fine on my iPhone screen but the print was definitely not blue, especially when under indoor lights. The guys at gelaskin were kind enough to give me another one for free that I could do with an updated version of the image. This is what you&amp;rsquo;re seeing here. I changed the blue to something that I felt was a safer bet (and better looking to). They looked at it before shipping and they did confirm it looked blue&amp;hellip;for real this time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a well-known fact that lack of sunlight affects mood. I know this to be true but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to tell ourselves we&amp;rsquo;re just too strong to feel the influence of something so out of our control as this distant sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except that the sun does help. But the sun is shy in San Francisco during what we conventionally call &amp;ldquo;summer&amp;rdquo;. Most of the time, the fog is king. Obviously, the closer you get to the coast, the worse it is (or the better it is if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for atmospheric fog).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, there&amp;rsquo;s September. People say the fog magically leaves by September. Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a big lie. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some of the thickest fog this September and we barely had any sun. I can&amp;rsquo;t say for sure if it&amp;rsquo;s an anomaly but if someone tells you September is never foggy here, it&amp;rsquo;s a blatant lie. This year was the proof (oh, isn&amp;rsquo;t fun to prove a proposition by a single contradiction?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came October. And now, oh boy, did October deliver. It was great. Not _too _hot but &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; right (except for that one time where it was &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too hot but that lasted like just one second). Along with the first days of October came the sun and it felt great. You might be like me and love seeing nature&amp;rsquo;s force in action (snowstorms, pouring rain, thunder, thick fog) but we need the sun. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think so much before but I do now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I remember Montreal. I know, it&amp;rsquo;s been only 6 months or so since we left. You know how it is though. As you leave a place, you start feeling the ties more strongly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this manifested in an odd manner. I felt like I should show my identity (as if people can&amp;rsquo;t tell from the way I talk). That&amp;rsquo;s a tricky thing. I&amp;rsquo;m not one to just dress myself with a flag or hang it by the window. But then, there had been this thing I had seen and liked for its looks but didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel right: a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gelaskins.com/store/phones/iPhone_4/O_Canada&#34;&gt;Canadian flag skin&lt;/a&gt; for the iPhone. There was also the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gelaskins.com/store/phones/iPhone_4/Stars_and_Stripes&#34;&gt;United States flag&lt;/a&gt;, not right either. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gelaskins.com/store/phones/iPhone_4/Union_Jack&#34;&gt;UK flag&lt;/a&gt;? Even worse. You can guess the rest of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, you can&amp;rsquo;t? Well, I made my own gelaskin. My Quebec flag gelaskin. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I would actually use it if I were still living in Quebec but here? I like the idea. I know I&amp;rsquo;ve said in the past that cases and screen protectors are &lt;strong&gt;bad&lt;/strong&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;m making a compromise here. A gelaskin isn&amp;rsquo;t actually a case: it should not add much perceptible thickness to my phone and it&amp;rsquo;s not covering any of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like it? Feel free to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/JeMeSouviensVersion2.jpg&#34;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt; to make your own. Or just try it to see how it looks using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gelaskins.com/create&#34;&gt;gelaskin&amp;rsquo;s custom skin creator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/The-Result-1024x681.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        The Real Thing.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;San Francisco is not Montreal. Talking specifically about weather (yep, this has been my great weather post!), we won&amp;rsquo;t get the great snowstorms of Montreal&amp;rsquo;s winter. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s always the same though. It might seem like it is sometimes. Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday: same forecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one day, it&amp;rsquo;s different. One day, there&amp;rsquo;s that pouring rain threatening a Giants game or that thicker fog that completely erases the view. And sometimes, there&amp;rsquo;s the sun and it&amp;rsquo;s rays shinning on through the leaves, bouncing off windows to come and tickle our senses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Light on that Blue</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/new-light-on-that-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/new-light-on-that-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*What follows is my take on &lt;a href=&#34;http://heyitsalex.net/what-can-happen-in-a-second/&#34;&gt;another&lt;/a&gt; prompt from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Things-Journal-Francisco-Writers-Grotto/dp/1452105448&#34;&gt;642 Things to Write About&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty personal, borderline personal diary. Yeah.
Since this blog is my miscellaneous bucket and I&amp;rsquo;m the editor, I say it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;in&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s ship it. Then, see how it feels.
Do not worry, I&amp;rsquo;m not planning on making regular posts about my feelings, probably.*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So here it is, my take on this prompt:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What a character holding a blue object is thinking about?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There I was, holding a blue pen. I had just lost my train of thought. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly looking at it so much as this was an out of focus blue spot. Not any blue either. It was a blue recalling Québec&amp;rsquo;s national blue. I always felt pretty neutral with that particular hue. I always loved blue but I disliked this particular one, much to my chagrin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today though, this blue is reminiscent of what we&amp;rsquo;ve left behind. We always knew it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be easy to relocate. The nice things about California are indeed &lt;em&gt;nice&lt;/em&gt; but it&amp;rsquo;s not so much like we weren&amp;rsquo;t happy with Montréal. This story isn&amp;rsquo;t one of a quest for the promised land.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/14092047/m%3D900/374628c29b6de4a859eb8bcdb6dbf069&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        There&amp;#39;s that theme of being somewhere else, shot by me in the Golden Gate Park woods.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Some days, we read about cool things that are happening right here, only here. Those days, I feel very fortunate to be here. Other days, we read about some interesting change happening in Montréal and we feel like we&amp;rsquo;re missing out. This is a very typical case of nostalgia versus novelty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that is relatively minor though, in the grand scheme of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything, except one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can do with a slower public transit system.
I can deal with a more complex health care system.
I can accept living in a less lively neighbourhood.
I am however having a real hard time not having friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What friends I hear you thinking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have many. I had to make sacrifices when it became obvious that, as a parent, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to do all I was doing before. Friendship took second place to personal projects and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except that this is oversimplifying. I still had friends. I was seeing some of them almost exclusively at the office but they &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be easy to make new friends. I was anticipating that the English speaking version of me would be struggling to find the words to express nuanced thoughts. It would be more difficult to be &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew it would be a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it harder than I thought it would be? Maybe not. But having anticipated it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any easier to deal with, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also very much neglected the difficulty in coordinating talking with friends in Eastern time. We&amp;rsquo;re living in an always connected world after all, aren’t we? It could be easier if I didn&amp;rsquo;t care so much about my work but I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s what I came here for and I do love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no happy revelation here. No words of wisdom. I didn&amp;rsquo;t make a new friend just today that made everything all better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those things that will incrementally get better over time. I suppose. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure friends are forever but you could say that we forever needs friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I see this blue pen today and it appears in this newly rediscovered grandiose hue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Can Happen in a Second?</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/what-can-happen-in-a-second/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/what-can-happen-in-a-second/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I stumbled upon a book last weekend that caught my attention. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Things-Journal-Francisco-Writers-Grotto/dp/1452105448&#34;&gt;642 Things to Write About&lt;/a&gt;. It contains 642 prompts for things to write about. Simple. With a clearly defined scope, creativity flourishes. If you know me, you know how I like this sort of thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is my take on the first prompt of the book: What Can Happen in a Second? I just wrote without thinking too much about it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Others might follow. Or not. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read the second prompt yet. I will. But I&amp;rsquo;m shipping this one first.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://500px.com/photo/11156255&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ppcdn.500px.org/11156255/cef93067bbb9d90935631a9ddfb7819cf694fd41/4.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        The Patience of a Lonely Boat, shot by me on an old Nikon FE2 with a fantastic Velvia 50. Doesn&amp;#39;t it serve as a good illustration for the slow passage of time?
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s an interesting question and not and an easy one to find answers to. It turns out that in our human world, not much can happen in a second. That may be counterintuitive for some. It just sounds right to our ears to hear that some big thing happened in a split second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s dramatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;That accident occurred in a split second.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From one second to the next, everything went from great to chaos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s interesting about those examples is that they really are not things that happened in a second. If you stop and think about it, in most cases, an accident had been in gestation for several seconds, minutes, hours, days. Sensationalism and big drama makes us report it otherwise. That, however, can be a rant for some other day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me share this personal story. A story you might know about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was this moment last year when my life took a turn. I had received an invitation for a job recruitment event in Montreal for a position on the United States West Coast. I was not really considering relocating but my wife said: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Why not?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Indeed, why not? At that moment, I started steering towards that new path. The horizon opened. You could argue that this change occurred at that second. I disagree. I think I had been contemplating the idea for some time. This idea was far-fetched, unrealistic. But that moment when that question triggered important and new answers was important not in itself, but as a tipping point in a series of events, experiences, reflections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say that not much happens in a second, that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m referring to. There&amp;rsquo;s that decisive moment that breaks the &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; and we&amp;rsquo;re tempted to think it all happened &lt;em&gt;right then&lt;/em&gt; but I believe the reality is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure we pass by such moments everyday because we&amp;rsquo;re not in the right mindset (which is quite alright too). As much as big drama seems to feed on split seconds twists, it&amp;rsquo;s often all the little moments that make a big one possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what can happen in one second? Millions of computations? Several frames in a video? Thousands of tweets? Yes, yes, yes and yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when we’re talking about stories, there’s always more hidden behind that instant of drama.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tourist Photographer&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-tourist-photographers-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 04:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/the-tourist-photographers-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wholeheartedly loathe tourist photos. I really do. I get angry just thinking about it. I really really hate this. Let me go outside and throw some rocks on a concrete wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I&amp;rsquo;m back (I actually just grabbed a snack instead).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me first explain what I think is the problem with tourist photos: they&amp;rsquo;re just too much. It&amp;rsquo;s all inclusive. It has you, your kids, all of your magnificent landmark and it&amp;rsquo;s surroundings. That kind of thing &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; works. Cameras should just pretend to be out of battery when faced with such a scene (they can recognizes &lt;em&gt;faces&lt;/em&gt; already so that&amp;rsquo;s possible right?).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7423/9349733524_71036a6a7c_h_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        This is a Boston landmark picture subtly showcasing the family. I&amp;#39;m not terribly proud of it but I don&amp;#39;t need to hide when people ask if I took it (I mean, if I were to hide, it would not be because of that).
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The reason it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work is simple: a picture that has more than _one_ thing makes that one thing much more difficult to stand out. We all have different tastes and opinions. As such, you might disagree but let&amp;rsquo;s just stop for a minute to look at pictures we like (I&amp;rsquo;ll go do something better while you take a few moments and do it). I think you&amp;rsquo;ll find that those are recurring patterns: shallow depth of field, uncoloured backgrounds, isolated subject, sharp focus. All of them have the same effect: make _one_ single thing stand out. Even ultra wide angles that seem to capture all of the surroundings produce great images when their focus is on making one thing stand out: the perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tourist photos are sickening because they do all the opposite. They cram people faking smiles on top of a very busy landmark scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we&amp;rsquo;re faced with this dilemma as photographers _and_ tourists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refuse to take the tourist snapshots and just take time to focus on quality work while pissing off everyone in the group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take the snapshots the best you can with your big camera to take the touristy snapshots with better execution.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m actually not sure we can resolve this to the satisfaction of everyone involved (unless you&amp;rsquo;re a family of photographers) but with a little effort, we can at least make an attempt. Or I tell you how and _you_ make the attempt. Just kidding, I&amp;rsquo;m not letting &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; try this alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s try and make tourist pictures better. First, let&amp;rsquo;s forget about showing off that you &lt;em&gt;were there in front of the golden bridge, omg!!&lt;/em&gt; People are doing it everyday and you can just tweet it, we&amp;rsquo;ll believe it. If we want to see the golden gate, we can google it and find fabulous shots that have been taken a thousand times.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexnormand/4829260124/in/set-72157624547713078/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4136/4829260124_08b784cc9b_o_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        One of my favorite touristy-type photos. I secretly waited for the good light while we were having fun and took this. Only regret: a stupid pole in the top-left corner of the frame I had to clumsily get rid of at post-processing.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not against using a landmark (or part of it) if it makes for a good picture though. A kid holding a coloured umbrella walking out of the fog on the golden gate bridge would be magnificent (I should do that shot before I start to think of the potential challenges involved). Let&amp;rsquo;s just forget about taking pictures of you and ALL of that gigantic scene. Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on isolated things. If you must take a picture with the statue of a president, make it a close up of yourself French kissing it. Want to capture yourself with the beautiful Apple store? Take a close shot of a reflection in it&amp;rsquo;s recognizable glass walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your job as the photographer (I know, it&amp;rsquo;s not your job, it&amp;rsquo;s just a hobby) is showing one interesting thing and removing everything else that gets in the way. Or at least, it&amp;rsquo;s a big part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well enough talk, now let&amp;rsquo;s try this. Don&amp;rsquo;t wait to be on vacation. Next time you&amp;rsquo;re outside, go play tourist in your own hometown. That&amp;rsquo;s something we always neglect anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe keep a &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; happy snapshots along the way as a peace offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just in case.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Almost Everything [or Nothing]</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-ultimate-guide-to-almost-everything-or-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 05:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/the-ultimate-guide-to-almost-everything-or-nothing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: After finishing and reading this post (ok, I &lt;em&gt;skimmed&lt;/em&gt; through it), I updated the title to better reflect its content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is going to be one of those serious posts where I tell know how to live your life to &amp;ldquo;enlarge&amp;rdquo; your happiness. This is all going to be bulletproof advice that I may or may not follow myself (but really, &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; me, I&amp;rsquo;m just putting that disclaimer there to please lawyers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On second thought (ok, on &lt;em&gt;initial&lt;/em&gt; thought, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really did any thinking before writing this out), scratch that, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to tell you how to live your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am, however, going to tell you &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;precisely&lt;/em&gt; how to do &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done research, experimentation and just plain thinking (transit time equals free thinking time) over the course of the last few years. I&amp;rsquo;m not putting any references here but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;just say things&lt;/em&gt; so, trust me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve come to believe is that the key to doing great work consistently lies in two elementary rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-seinfeld-chain-http-lifehacker-com-281626-jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&#34;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&#34;&gt;The Seinfeld Chain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/calendar167d36622f4559b122840489a4b456b59efb1581.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        My Calendar for July, a Really Bad Example of a Seinfeld Chain Illustration Because it&amp;#39;s Empty since the Month Hasn&amp;#39;t started Yet.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be daily but you should have a schedule with outputs and you should stick to it. Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re just a slacker constantly putting off tasks, that won&amp;rsquo;t help. You might get some things done once in a while but your chain will look like a bunch of stupid rings. You will look at this and think back at this &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&#34;&gt;Seinfeld chain&lt;/a&gt; and since your efforts are so pathetic, you&amp;rsquo;ll just give up and never get anything done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, now that we got rid of the self conscious slackers, let&amp;rsquo;s get to the second point&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-don-t-overwork-do-work-and-celebrate&#34;&gt;2. Don&amp;rsquo;t overwork. Do work and celebrate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is pretty intuitive really. You get some good work done and you enjoy the satisfaction. That&amp;rsquo;s it. When you do that, you&amp;rsquo;ve got something to be proud of and something to look forward to for next time. Now, you rest or just do something else. If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, you&amp;rsquo;re currently in leisure mode so get ready and go back to work (but finish reading first).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we feel like just going on a continuous non stopped stretch is just the structure of work life. Work more, get more done, &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3180-a-good-days-work&#34;&gt;right&lt;/a&gt;? Well, as much as we would like this to be true, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be generally the case. It&amp;rsquo;s less easy to apply this to a 40 hours job where work time is crucial. Don&amp;rsquo;t go using that as an excuse though. If you learn to split tasks into smaller tasks, then it is possible to eventually get to a point when you can leave work everyday having accomplished stuff and feeling good about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, that last part was pretty dry but it&amp;rsquo;s the key to something so it had to be said (and read, I really hope you read it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time, stay curious and don&amp;rsquo;t let you phone run out of battery (unrelated advice but it&amp;rsquo;s really not cool if someone needs to call you and you can&amp;rsquo;t get the call).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coming next: how to master a second language as a grown-up?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(okay, it won&amp;rsquo;t be my next post, it&amp;rsquo;s more of an actual question from me to the world! I don&amp;rsquo;t know how, I&amp;rsquo;m so horrendously horrible at this).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The San Francisco Guide for Montréalers</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-san-francisco-guide-for-montrealers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 05:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/the-san-francisco-guide-for-montrealers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You dear reader should already know that I&amp;rsquo;m a new San Franciscan and ex-Montréaler. As such, I present you with great authority the definite guide to San Francisco for Montréalers. It&amp;rsquo;s really more of a collection of fairly obvious differences between Montréal and San Francisco. I really rely on my blog getting zero readership to shield me from real potential of offending residents of both cities. It may have been better titled as &amp;ldquo;10 differences between Montréal and San Francisco&amp;rdquo; but I hate those. They most often come in round numbers which I find suspicious. How convenient would it be if there were really 10 differences between the two cities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering this, I&amp;rsquo;m not even counting how many I&amp;rsquo;m listing here. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that to you and I might just trick you and update this list (hey, this could be a living document). The following represent my opinions but I believe it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say most with the same background as me would agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stm-kicks-ass-and-muni-not-so-much&#34;&gt;STM Kicks Ass and Muni not so Much&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t know what you have until you lose it, right? Actually, I knew the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.examiner.com/article/stm-wins-the-stanley-cup-of-public-transport-for-north-america&#34;&gt;STM was pretty good&lt;/a&gt;. But after seeing tramways, BART and buses in movies depicting San Francisco, I thought the public transport here would be amazing. It&amp;rsquo;s not really. Muni is cheaper but it&amp;rsquo;s also as slow as it is unreliable. To be fair, it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely a problem of Muni but rather a problem with traffic and lack of speedy ways reserved for buses. Express buses are not really &lt;em&gt;express&lt;/em&gt;. Additionally if you have a positively surprising experience with an express bus one day, Muni will make sure to make it up the next day with the express just flying by your stop with a bus fully packed of people. Yes, leaving you, the hopeful commuter, standing there feeling the chilly wind crushing your hopes of a quick transit and the seed of cynicism growing inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there are also little details like no sign whatsoever for Express buses stops on Pine street. There are several express routes stopping here and you don&amp;rsquo;t have any way of telling which will stop where. Apparently it&amp;rsquo;s knowledge that gets passed from &lt;em&gt;generation to generation&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told it&amp;rsquo;s in somewhat numerical ordering by some wise guy who seemed to have reversed engineered it. Still haven&amp;rsquo;t verified it. I just memorized the address of the building where the 31AX stops (for the record, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://maps.google.com/maps?q=360+pine+st,+San+francisco&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ll=37.791558,-122.401353&amp;amp;spn=0.006249,0.013937&amp;amp;sll=37.792069,-122.402002&amp;amp;layer=c&amp;amp;cbp=13,16.36,,0,0.05&amp;amp;cbll=37.791962,-122.40204&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;hnear=360+Pine+St,+San+Francisco,+California+94104&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;z=17&amp;amp;iwloc=A&amp;amp;panoid=7CHnHdxivs7YOWxItuJU8Q&#34;&gt;360 Pine St&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-sf-bus-drivers-all-hate-life-montréal-drivers-actually-enjoy-driving-people&#34;&gt;The SF Bus Drivers All Hate Life, Montréal Drivers Actually Enjoy Driving People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true. You may want to be polite or friendly and salute your driver when you enter or thank him/her when you get off but you&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised to get a smile or even an answer back. STM drivers will generally welcome everyone on board and salute them when they get off. I had drivers recognize me and talk to me just like that (remember, I am not good with people!). I even had one watch for me arriving to the stop from the other side of the street to signal me to wait and not cross foolishly when it wasn&amp;rsquo;t safe as he proceeded to wait for the light change and get me on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that&amp;rsquo;s not enough, here&amp;rsquo;s a true STM story: there&amp;rsquo;s a driver that sings the name of bus stops every morning. I have never actually seen it myself but the tellings are true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, some Montreal drivers (but those are in the minority) aren&amp;rsquo;t that friendly. Also, I said all muni drivers hate life and all living creatures on earth but I rode the 31 one evening and the driver was the nicest, going as far as &lt;em&gt;fist bumping&lt;/em&gt; me as I got off the bus (this made my day, I love this guy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-people-you-see-in-sf-are-not-attractive-montréal-wins&#34;&gt;All People You See in SF are not Attractive, Montréal Wins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really surprising. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;m married and it&amp;rsquo;s not like I&amp;rsquo;m here looking around but living in the city, you see people everyday. You sort of subconsciously assess the beauty of the population around you, I guess. There&amp;rsquo;s probably someone studying that social behavior but I&amp;rsquo;m just there to tell you that the truth is this: it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to make your way to work and back without seeing someone really good looking. Maybe my sample doesn&amp;rsquo;t accurately reflect the larger population of san Francisco, I mostly see people riding muni (could this explain why muni drivers have those gloomy eyes?) but there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to make me believe that it is the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montréal folks are more attractive unless you&amp;rsquo;re blind and then, it&amp;rsquo;s a tie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to give you some perspective, the subject was brought up by my wife after I had passed myself the same reflection. It can&amp;rsquo;t be anything but the absolute truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-don-t-happen-in-montréal-anymore-sf-moves-with-the-wind&#34;&gt;Changes Don&amp;rsquo;t Happen in Montréal (anymore), SF Moves with the Wind&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even small things never seem to take forever to get done in Montréal. Not like that here. Plans are approved for a soccer stadium in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/12/02/golden-gate-park-soccer-fields_n_1126206.html&#34;&gt;golden gate park&lt;/a&gt; and plans are for construction to start in a few months to be complete by winter next year. Want a bicycle rack? Just &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sfbike.org/?bikerack&#34;&gt;ask for one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;montreal-trees-are-tiny-brocolis-sf-ones-are-giant-and-majestic&#34;&gt;Montreal Trees are Tiny Brocolis, SF Ones Are Giant and Majestic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just look at the pictures (they&amp;rsquo;re online, sorry I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get some here for your convenience). Montréal has colourful maples leaves in fall, that&amp;rsquo;s all. Love trees? Golden Gate park or presidio park is where the magic happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-health-care-situation&#34;&gt;The Health Care Situation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s do a checklist comparison because we all love those, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doctor office reachable by email: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Online appointment scheduling: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Availability in the following week: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No line-up for lab tests: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Online prescription renewals: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On-time appointments: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Email communication channel between doctor and patient: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montréal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fully loaded doctor calendars months in advance: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Packed waiting rooms full of people to sympathize with: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elaborate congestion system to filter real health problems: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Retro-style one-way communication system: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is too close. I&amp;rsquo;ll call it a draw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;san-franciscans-all-have-a-garage-and-10-cars-montréalers-a-bit-less&#34;&gt;San Franciscans all Have a Garage and 10 Cars, Montréalers, a bit Less&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People kept telling me I would absolutely need a car when I got here. They would tell me again. And insist. And insist again, telling me I could try living without one but I would give up eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, challenge accepted!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, we can pretty much do all we want without one and &lt;a href=&#34;http://zipcar.com&#34;&gt;zipcar&lt;/a&gt; is there for the luxurious trips like communauto was back in Montréal. However, we are definitely more in an even smaller minority here than we were in Montréal. People have driveways and garages. And they use it. Those garages are filled with cars and that&amp;rsquo;s not just for &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt;. People use their garage and then park another car on the street. It&amp;rsquo;s almost unbelievable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;olds-cars-are-still-alive&#34;&gt;Olds Cars are Still Alive&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8083/8301735631_94f6473094_o_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        The last sample before I felt very very blasé.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I hate cars or at least, I dislike them. I still have my driver&amp;rsquo;s license but I&amp;rsquo;m a happy fellow when I see anything that prevents cars from being on the street. However, I love the retro look of cars for their visual attractiveness and how they stand out. You might have seen some instagrams as a proof of that. I stopped doing those though. Not because I don&amp;rsquo;t see any retro cars anymore, it&amp;rsquo;s just the opposite: old pastel blue painted fords, rusty Beatles, buicks, Cadillacs. They survived in California. They&amp;rsquo;re all over the place along with the newer models. Not in junkyards, they&amp;rsquo;re just there around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was blasé after a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bicycles-are-king&#34;&gt;Bicycles are King&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montréal has bixi and bike lanes and flat roads to make it easy for cyclists. SF has steep hills all over and cars are omnipresent. Nonetheless, SF wins the bike culture crown. Those bikes are &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;. Buses wait behind, respectfully. When Muni service routes are shutdown for a week, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfbike.org/?transit&#34;&gt;bike train&lt;/a&gt; route is put in place for commuters. There&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wiggle&#34;&gt;wiggle trail&lt;/a&gt; for people to have a relatively flat route (I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to do it any other way). Apparently people have cars (and many) but they also know it&amp;rsquo;s not very wise to drive it during workdays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bikes are king.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-who-wins&#34;&gt;So who Wins?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could think I regret leaving Montréal and in some ways, I could. Except that I don&amp;rsquo;t really. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice here. And work is great. And there&amp;rsquo;s the ocean, and the golden gate, and all the great tech and the promise of great historical earthquakes. Oh shit shit shit, the earthquakes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey, it&#39;s a Start</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/hey-its-a-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 05:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/hey-its-a-start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I may suffer from some condition. Ok well, that&amp;rsquo;s an embarrassing way to start because I really do have a condition as I have type 1 diabetes. But I&amp;rsquo;ve had that since I was a teenager so it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; was I&amp;rsquo;m referring to here. I was actually thinking of this habit of mine of always having some personal project &lt;a href=&#34;http://dawnofbubbles.com/post/6923528541/creation-as-a-fulltime-dad&#34;&gt;on a schedule&lt;/a&gt; and never letting that go. To the point where I get mad for being so near my self-imposed deadline and being stressed out about not being able to deliver. So much so that it seems like all potential of fun is gone, all fun is sucked out of it and it really is making life a misery for me and all people around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that happens only once in a while so it&amp;rsquo;s all good. No problem here.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/crossroads.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        It&amp;#39;s a Road and I Cross it Everyday to Take the Bus. No Joke.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In fact, I&amp;rsquo;m really hitching for some new project. You know, something to brag about and put on my software engineer resume in which in no way helps my “career”. I really need this in my life. It guarantees that I have absolutely no time for entertainment while I entertain an adequate amount of sleep deprivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But back to this project discussion. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m actually thinking of mixing things up a bit. I really do think having a restricted scope helps spur creativity but I feel like I can try something more diversified this time around. I may simply be inspired by the relative chaos I&amp;rsquo;m currently living in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, I can&amp;rsquo;t just bring that up and leave it at that: I&amp;rsquo;ve been living since the beginning of my work life in Montreal and it was great. I have a nice cute family with two kids and they all love it there. So what was I to do next? Well, I applied for a job at some remote location and I got it. Then, I had my family give up everything to come with me in San Francisco where we don&amp;rsquo;t know anyone nor speak the language very well. That, my friend (am I moving too quickly saying that?) is the chaos I was taking about. It&amp;rsquo;s not just &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;, obviously, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to ask me for more details if you want me to expand on that topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But back on the project topic again. I actually have a few ideas lined up. What usually happens when I have queue of ideas is&amp;hellip;only one gets executed, if any. In the spirit of getting things done, I&amp;rsquo;m doing &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt;. Notice that &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t an hyperlink. That&amp;rsquo;s because your already on it (okay, I could have many it an anchor link or something but that would have been annoying and not as much fun as me explaining).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yes, I&amp;rsquo;m writing a blog. If you know me, you know I can&amp;rsquo;t really express myself very clearly so that might be a challenge&amp;hellip;or good entertainment for you, the reader. It could go either way. Here is me writing a blog like I&amp;rsquo;ve got something to say that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been said already (or just saying nothing, that&amp;rsquo;s been done too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog about anything, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a Montréaler in California. A dad with almost childish looks with kids that will grow up in another country. A French speaking guy who gets unmasked after speaking half a word of English (or did I say that in French?). A weird stranger in a fast-paced and hard-working tech world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Alex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just Alex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s because Alexandre can&amp;rsquo;t be pronounced correctly in English. That&amp;rsquo;s okay, I can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce anything correctly in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a very climatic opening isn&amp;rsquo;t it? I feel pretty good about this. I think I actually have something good here for a first post. I just have to make sure I&amp;rsquo;m not screwing up the ending (TODO: review that last paragraph before posting).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
