<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/3.5.2" created="2013-07-20 02:28" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Hey it&#039;s Alex!</title>
	<link>http://heyitsalex.net</link>
	<description>Not as Bad as One could Imagine</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 02:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://heyitsalex.net</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://heyitsalex.net</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>alexandre.normand</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>alexandre.normand@gmail.com</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[alexandre.normand]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel="payment" title="Flattr this!" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?user_id=alex_normand&amp;popout=1&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fheyitsalex.net%2F&amp;language=en_US&amp;category=text&amp;title=Hey+it%26%23039%3Bs+Alex%21&amp;description=Not+as+Bad+as+One+could+Imagine&amp;tags=blog" type="text/html" />

	<item>
		<title>Hey, it&#039;s a Start</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/hey-its-a-start/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 05:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=22</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I may suffer from some condition. Ok well, that's an embarrassing way to start because I really do have a condition as I have type 1 diabetes. But I've had that since I was a teenager so it's <em>not</em> was I'm referring to here. I was actually thinking of this habit of mine of always having some personal project <a href="http://dawnofbubbles.com/post/6923528541/creation-as-a-fulltime-dad">on a schedule</a> and never letting that go. To the point where I get mad for being so near my self-imposed deadline and being stressed out about not being able to deliver. So much so that it seems like all potential of fun is gone, all fun is sucked out of it and it really is making life a misery for me and all people around me.

But that happens only once in a while so it's all good. No problem here.

[caption id="attachment_47" align="alignright" width="306" caption="It&#39;s a Road and I Cross it Everyday to Take the Bus. No Joke."]<a href="http://instagr.am/p/KaJJCDO8f8/"><img class="size-full wp-image-47" title="Crossroads" src="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/crossroads.jpg" alt="" width="306" height="306" /></a>[/caption]

In fact, I'm really hitching for some new project. You know, something to brag about and put on my software engineer resume in which in no way helps my “career”. I really need this in my life. It guarantees that I have absolutely no time for entertainment while I entertain an adequate amount of sleep deprivation.

But back to this project discussion. This time, I'm actually thinking of mixing things up a bit. I really do think having a restricted scope helps spur creativity but I feel like I can try something more diversified this time around. I may simply be inspired by the relative chaos I'm currently living in.

Alright, I can't just bring that up and leave it at that: I've been living since the beginning of my work life in Montreal and it was great. I have a nice cute family with two kids and they all love it there. So what was I to do next? Well, I applied for a job at some remote location and I got it. Then, I had my family give up everything to come with me in San Francisco where we don't know anyone nor speak the language very well. That, my friend (am I moving too quickly saying that?) is the chaos I was taking about. It's not just <em>that</em>, obviously, but you'll have to ask me for more details if you want me to expand on that topic.

But back on the project topic again. I actually have a few ideas lined up. What usually happens when I have queue of ideas is...only one gets executed, if any. In the spirit of getting things done, I'm doing <em>this</em>. Notice that <em>this</em> isn't an hyperlink. That's because your already on it (okay, I could have many it an anchor link or something but that would have been annoying and not as much fun as me explaining).

So yes, I'm writing a blog. If you know me, you know I can't really express myself very clearly so that might be a challenge...or good entertainment for you, the reader. It could go either way. Here is me writing a blog like I've got something to say that hasn't been said already (or just saying nothing, that's been done too).

A blog about anything, really.

I'm a Montréaler in California. A dad with almost childish looks with kids that will grow up in another country. A French speaking guy who gets unmasked after speaking half a word of English (or did I say that in French?). A weird stranger in a fast-paced and hard-working tech world.

I'm Alex.

Just Alex.

Well, that's because Alexandre can't be pronounced correctly in English. That's okay, I can't pronounce anything correctly in English.

It's a very climatic opening isn't it? I feel pretty good about this. I think I actually have something good here for a first post. I just have to make sure I'm not screwing up the ending (TODO: review that last paragraph before posting).]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>22</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-06-11 22:20:03</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-06-12 05:20:03</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>hey-its-a-start</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="nothing"><![CDATA[nothing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>7</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Online casino]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://heyitsalex.net/hey-its-a-start/trackback/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>188.143.232.144</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2013-06-30 17:01:13</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2013-07-01 00:01:13</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[<strong>Aussie online casinos...</strong>

Top 10 online Aussie casinos....]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>trackback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The San Francisco Guide for Montréalers</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-san-francisco-guide-for-montrealers/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 05:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=31</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[You dear reader should already know that I'm a new San Franciscan and ex-Montréaler. As such, I present you with great authority the definite guide to San Francisco for Montréalers. It's really more of a collection of fairly obvious differences between Montréal and San Francisco. I really rely on my blog getting zero readership to shield me from real potential of offending residents of both cities. It may have been better titled as "10 differences between Montréal and San Francisco" but I hate those. They most often come in round numbers which I find suspicious. How convenient would it be if there were really 10 differences between the two cities?

Considering this, I'm not even counting how many I'm listing here. I'll leave that to you and I might just trick you and update this list (hey, this could be a living document). The following represent my opinions but I believe it's fair to say most with the same background as me would agree.
<h2>STM Kicks Ass and Muni not so Much</h2>
You don't know what you have until you lose it, right? Actually, I knew the <a title="STM wins American Public Transportation Association award as Outstanding Public Transportation System in North America" href="http://www.stm.info/english/info/comm-10/a-co101005b.htm">STM was pretty good</a>. But after seeing tramways, BART and buses in movies depicting San Francisco, I thought the public transport here would be amazing. It's not really. Muni is cheaper but it's also as slow as it is unreliable. To be fair, it's not entirely a problem of Muni but rather a problem with traffic and lack of speedy ways reserved for buses. Express buses are not really <em>express</em>. Additionally if you have a positively surprising experience with an express bus one day, Muni will make sure to make it up the next day with the express just flying by your stop with a bus fully packed of people. Yes, leaving you, the hopeful commuter, standing there feeling the chilly wind crushing your hopes of a quick transit and the seed of cynicism growing inside.

Additionally, there are also little details like no sign whatsoever for Express buses stops on Pine street. There are several express routes stopping here and you don't have any way of telling which will stop where. Apparently it's knowledge that gets passed from <em>generation to generation</em>. I've been told it's in somewhat numerical ordering by some wise guy who seemed to have reversed engineered it. Still haven't verified it. I just memorized the address of the building where the 31AX stops (for the record, it's <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=360+pine+st,+San+francisco&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=37.791558,-122.401353&amp;spn=0.006249,0.013937&amp;sll=37.792069,-122.402002&amp;layer=c&amp;cbp=13,16.36,,0,0.05&amp;cbll=37.791962,-122.40204&amp;gl=us&amp;hnear=360+Pine+St,+San+Francisco,+California+94104&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A&amp;panoid=7CHnHdxivs7YOWxItuJU8Q">360 Pine St</a>).
<h2>The SF Bus Drivers All Hate Life, Montréal Drivers Actually Enjoy Driving People</h2>
It's true. You may want to be polite or friendly and salute your driver when you enter or thank him/her when you get off but you'll be surprised to get a smile or even an answer back. STM drivers will generally welcome everyone on board and salute them when they get off. I had drivers recognize me and talk to me just like that (remember, I am not good with people!). I even had one watch for me arriving to the stop from the other side of the street to signal me to wait and not cross foolishly when it wasn't safe as he proceeded to wait for the light change and get me on board.

If that's not enough, here's a true STM story: there's a driver that sings the name of bus stops every morning. I have never actually seen it myself but the tellings are true.

All that said, some Montreal drivers (but those are in the minority) aren't that friendly. Also, I said all muni drivers hate life and all living creatures on earth but I rode the 31 one evening and the driver was the nicest, going as far as <em>fist bumping</em> me as I got off the bus (this made my day, I love this guy).
<h2>All People You See in SF are not Attractive, Montréal Wins</h2>
It's really surprising. I mean, I'm married and it's not like I'm here looking around but living in the city, you see people everyday. You sort of subconsciously assess the beauty of the population around you, I guess. There's probably someone studying that social behavior but I'm just there to tell you that the truth is this: it's very easy to make your way to work and back without seeing someone really good looking. Maybe my sample doesn't accurately reflect the larger population of san Francisco, I mostly see people riding muni (could this explain why muni drivers have those gloomy eyes?) but there's nothing to make me believe that it is the case.

Montréal folks are more attractive unless you're blind and then, it's a tie.

Just to give you some perspective, the subject was brought up by my wife after I had passed myself the same reflection. It can't be anything but the absolute truth.
<h2>Changes Don't Happen in Montréal (anymore), SF Moves with the Wind</h2>
Even small things never seem to take forever to get done in Montréal. Not like that here. Plans are approved for a soccer stadium in the <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/12/02/golden-gate-park-soccer-fields_n_1126206.html">golden gate park</a> and plans are for construction to start in a few months to be complete by winter next year. Want a bicycle rack? Just <a href="https://www.sfbike.org/?bikerack">ask for one</a>.
<h2>Montreal Trees are Tiny Brocolis, SF Ones Are Giant and Majestic</h2>
Just look at the pictures (they're online, sorry I couldn't get some here for your convenience). Montréal has colourful maples leaves in fall, that's all. Love trees? Golden Gate park or presidio park is where the magic happens.
<h2>The Health Care Situation</h2>
Let's do a checklist comparison because we all love those, right?
<div>SF</div>
<ul>
	<li>Doctor office reachable by email: ✓</li>
	<li>Online appointment scheduling: ✓</li>
	<li>Availability in the following week: ✓</li>
	<li>No line-up for lab tests: ✓</li>
	<li>Online prescription renewals: ✓</li>
	<li>On-time appointments: ✓</li>
	<li>Email communication channel between doctor and patient: ✓</li>
</ul>
<div>Montréal</div>
<div>
<ul>
	<li>Fully loaded doctor calendars months in advance: ✓</li>
	<li>Packed waiting rooms full of people to sympathize with: ✓</li>
	<li>Elaborate congestion system to filter real health problems: ✓</li>
	<li>Retro-style one-way communication system: ✓</li>
</ul>
This one is too close. I'll call it a draw.
<h2>San Franciscans all Have a Garage and 10 Cars, Montréalers, a bit Less</h2>
People kept telling me I would absolutely need a car when I got here. They would tell me again. And insist. And insist again, telling me I could try living without one but I would give up eventually.

Well, challenge accepted!

So far, we can pretty much do all we want without one and <a href="http://zipcar.com">zipcar</a> is there for the luxurious trips like communauto was back in Montréal. However, we are definitely more in an even smaller minority here than we were in Montréal. People have driveways and garages. And they use it. Those garages are filled with cars and that's not just for <em>one</em>. People use their garage and then park another car on the street. It's almost unbelievable.
<h2>Olds Cars are Still Alive</h2>
[caption id="" align="alignright" width="300" caption="The last sample before I felt very very blasé"]<a href="http://instagr.am/p/JvvACfO8Yb/"><img title="An old one" src="http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/42b434bc8cee11e1ab011231381052c0_7.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>[/caption]

I hate cars or at least, I dislike them. I still have my driver's license but I'm a happy fellow when I see anything that prevents cars from being on the street. However, I love the retro look of cars for their visual attractiveness and how they stand out. You might have seen some instagrams as a proof of that. I stopped doing those though. Not because I don't see any retro cars anymore, it's just the opposite: old pastel blue painted fords, rusty Beatles, buicks, Cadillacs. They survived in California. They're all over the place along with the newer models. Not in junkyards, they're just there around the corner.

I was blasé after a month.
<h2>Bicycles are King</h2>
Montréal has bixi and bike lanes and flat roads to make it easy for cyclists. SF has steep hills all over and cars are omnipresent. Nonetheless, SF wins the bike culture crown. Those bikes are <em>everywhere</em>. Buses wait behind, respectfully. When Muni service routes are shutdown for a week, a <a href="http://www.sfbike.org/?transit">bike train</a> route is put in place for commuters. There's the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wiggle">wiggle trail</a> for people to have a relatively flat route (I wouldn't want to do it any other way). Apparently people have cars (and many) but they also know it's not very wise to drive it during workdays.

Bikes are king.
<h2>So who Wins?</h2>
You could think I regret leaving Montréal and in some ways, I could. Except that I don't really. It's really nice here. And work is great. And there's the ocean, and the golden gate, and all the great tech and the promise of great historical earthquakes. Oh shit shit shit, the earthquakes...

</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>31</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-06-13 22:00:55</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-06-14 05:00:55</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-san-francisco-guide-for-montrealers</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="nothing"><![CDATA[nothing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>2</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Michael Fortin]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>michael.fortin@mollix.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://flickr.com/mollix</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>184.151.114.178</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-07-05 03:58:55</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-07-05 10:58:55</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi Alex!

It's nice to read you. I really enyoyed the account of the differences between the cities from your perspective while enjoying my morning breakfast at Cora on Nuns' Island!

To tell you the truth, your title is what caught my attention first. I was eager to read a "SF guide" made especially for me, since we're planning our August summer vacation on the west coast!

Preliminary plans are to land in SF, rent a car, spend a few days there, find some nice family activities (son is 8, daughter is 11) and then head to LA following the coast, spend 7-10 days visiting Hollywood, Disney Land and other stuff and then head to San Diego and spend 3-5 days there to visit the zoo and find other family actives and fly back from there to Montréal.

Any suggestions or recommendations?

Mike]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1341485935.2753";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1341499542.3191";s:7:"message";s:56:"alexandre.normand changed the comment status to approved";s:5:"event";s:15:"status-approved";s:4:"user";s:17:"alexandre.normand";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>3</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[alexandre.normand]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>alexandre.normand@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>75.101.100.25</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-07-05 21:05:29</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-07-06 04:05:29</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[It sounds like you've done some research already. As much as I would like to give some original San Francisco highlights from an insider's perspective, I pretty much lived mostly the work life. We're still spending weekends discovering the city and the surroundings. That said, the Golden Gate is great and if you can drive North, there are some beautiful sights (and twisted roads). I'm sure kids would love to see the California Academy of Science in the Golden Gate park. It's not huge but the aquarium setup is great (you can see the fishes from above in open space and then go to the lower level to see them from a more traditional perspective) and the earthquake exhibit (and show in the planetarium) is also very cool. I think we could also get you discounted tickets for the California Academy of Science if you're interested as we have a membership that lists that as a benefit. 

One thing I would mention though if you plan on driving inside San Francisco: easy parking doesn't exist. If you can, use the BART and the buses (as much as I would love Muni to be better than it is, it still gets you where you want to go).]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>2</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>1</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1341547529.4553";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:17:"alexandre.normand";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Ultimate Guide to Almost Everything [or Nothing]</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-ultimate-guide-to-almost-everything-or-nothing/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 05:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=65</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Update: After finishing and reading this post (ok, I <em>skimmed</em> through it), I updated the title to better reflect its content.</strong>

So this is going to be one of those serious posts where I tell know how to live your life to "enlarge" your happiness. This is all going to be bulletproof advice that I may or may not follow myself (but really, <em>trust</em> me, I'm just putting that disclaimer there to please lawyers).

On second thought (ok, on <em>initial</em> thought, I hadn't really did any thinking before writing this out), scratch that, I'm not going to tell you how to live your life.

I am, however, going to tell you <em>exactly</em>, <em>precisely</em> how to do <em>stuff</em>.

I've done research, experimentation and just plain thinking (transit time equals free thinking time) over the course of the last few years. I'm not putting any references here but I wouldn't <em>just say things</em> so, trust me.

What I've come to believe is that the key to doing great work consistently lies in two elementary rules:
<h2>1. <a href="http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret">The Seinfeld Chain</a></h2>
[caption id="attachment_67" align="alignright" width="320"]<a href="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/calendar167d36622f4559b122840489a4b456b59efb1581.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-67 " title="calendar167d36622f4559b122840489a4b456b59efb1581" src="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/calendar167d36622f4559b122840489a4b456b59efb1581.jpg" alt="Yes, Custom Calendar, Homemade" width="320" /></a> My Calendar for July, a Really Bad Example of a Seinfeld Chain Illustration Because it's Empty since the Month Hasn't started Yet.[/caption]

It doesn't have to be daily but you should have a schedule with outputs and you should stick to it. Of course, if you're just a slacker constantly putting off tasks, that won't help. You might get some things done once in a while but your chain will look like a bunch of stupid rings. You will look at this and think back at this <a href="http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret">Seinfeld chain</a> and since your efforts are so pathetic, you'll just give up and never get anything done.

Ok, now that we got rid of the self conscious slackers, let's get to the second point...
<h2>2. Don't overwork. Do work and celebrate</h2>
This is pretty intuitive really. You get some good work done and you enjoy the satisfaction. That's it. When you do that, you've got something to be proud of and something to look forward to for next time. Now, you rest or just do something else. If you're reading this, you're currently in leisure mode so get ready and go back to work (but finish reading first).

The reason we feel like just going on a continuous non stopped stretch is just the structure of work life. Work more, get more done, <a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3180-a-good-days-work">right</a>? Well, as much as we would like this to be true, this doesn't seem to be generally the case. It's less easy to apply this to a 40 hours job where work time is crucial. Don't go using that as an excuse though. If you learn to split tasks into smaller tasks, then it is possible to eventually get to a point when you can leave work everyday having accomplished stuff and feeling good about it.

Ok, that last part was pretty dry but it's the key to something so it had to be said (and read, I really hope you read it).

Until next time, stay curious and don't let you phone run out of battery (unrelated advice but it's really not cool if someone needs to call you and you can't get the call).

<em>Coming next: how to master a second language as a grown-up? </em>

<em>(okay, it won't be my next post, it's more of an actual question from me to the world! I don't know how, I'm so horrendously horrible at this).</em>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>65</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-06-26 22:05:49</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-06-27 05:05:49</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-ultimate-guide-to-almost-everything-or-nothing</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="nothing"><![CDATA[nothing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Tourist Photographer&#039;s Dilemma</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-tourist-photographers-dilemma/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 04:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=82</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I wholeheartedly loathe tourist photos. I really do. I get angry just thinking about it. I really really hate this. Let me go outside and throw some rocks on a concrete wall.
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">...</p>
</blockquote>
Okay, I'm back (I actually just grabbed a snack instead).

Let me first explain what I think is the problem with tourist photos: they're just too much. It's all inclusive. It has you, your kids, all of your magnificent landmark and it's surroundings. That kind of thing <em>never</em> works. Cameras should just pretend to be out of battery when faced with such a scene (they can recognizes <em>faces </em>already so that's possible right?).

[caption id="attachment_91" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/DSC_18011.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-91" title="A Rather Boring Boston Landmark" src="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/DSC_18011-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a> This is a Boston landmark picture subtly showcasing the family. I'm not terribly proud of it but I don't need to hide when people ask if I took it (I mean, if I were to hide, it would not be because of that).[/caption]

The reason it doesn't work is simple: a picture that has more than <em>one</em> thing makes that one thing much more difficult to stand out. We all have different tastes and opinions. As such, you might disagree but let's just stop for a minute to look at pictures we like (I'll go do something better while you take a few moments and do it). I think you'll find that those are recurring patterns: shallow depth of field, uncoloured backgrounds, isolated subject, sharp focus. All of them have the same effect: make <em>one</em> single thing stand out. Even ultra wide angles that seem to capture all of the surroundings produce great images when their focus is on making one thing stand out: the perspective.

Tourist photos are sickening because they do all the opposite. They cram people faking smiles on top of a very busy landmark scene.

So we're faced with this dilemma as photographers <em>and</em> tourists:
<ol>
	<li>refuse to take the tourist snapshots and just take time to focus on quality work while pissing off everyone in the group</li>
</ol>
or
<ol start="2">
	<li>take the snapshots the best you can with your big camera to take the touristy snapshots with better execution.</li>
</ol>
I'm actually not sure we can resolve this to the satisfaction of everyone involved (unless you're a family of photographers) but with a little effort, we can at least make an attempt. Or I tell you how and <em>you</em> make the attempt. Just kidding, I'm not letting <em>you</em> try this alone.

So let's try and make tourist pictures better. First, let's forget about showing off that you <em>were there in front of the golden bridge, omg!!</em> People are doing it everyday and you can just tweet it, we'll believe it. If we want to see the golden gate, we can google it and find fabulous shots that have been taken a thousand times.

[caption id="" align="alignright" width="312"]<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexnormand/4829260124/in/set-72157624547713078/"><img class="  " title="The Kids Are All Gone" src="http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4136/4829260124_b7a9460d4a_d.jpg" alt="" width="312" height="244" /></a> One of my favorite touristy-type photos. I secretly waited for the good light while we were "having fun" and took this. Only regret: a stupid pole in the top-left corner of the frame I had to clumsily get rid of at post-processing.[/caption]

I'm not against using a landmark (or part of it) if it makes for a good picture though. A kid holding a coloured umbrella walking out of the fog on the golden gate bridge would be magnificent (I should do that shot before I start to think of the potential challenges involved). Let's just forget about taking pictures of you and ALL of that gigantic scene. Let's focus on isolated things. If you must take a picture with the statue of a president, make it a close up of yourself French kissing it. Want to capture yourself with the beautiful Apple store? Take a close shot of a reflection in it's recognizable glass walls.

Your job as the photographer (I know, it's not your job, it's just a hobby) is showing one interesting thing and removing everything else that gets in the way. Or at least, it's a big part of it.

Well enough talk, now let's try this. Don't wait to be on vacation. Next time you're outside, go play tourist in your own hometown. That's something we always neglect anyway.

Maybe keep a <em>few</em> happy snapshots along the way as a peace offering.

<em>Just in case.</em>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>82</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-26 21:30:35</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-27 04:30:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-tourist-photographers-dilemma</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="photography"><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>What Can Happen in a Second?</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/what-can-happen-in-a-second/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 05:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=99</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>I stumbled upon a book last weekend that caught my attention. It's called <a title="642 Things to Write About" href="http://www.amazon.com/Things-Journal-Francisco-Writers-Grotto/dp/1452105448">642 Things to Write About</a>. It contains 642 prompts for things to write about. Simple. With a clearly defined scope, creativity flourishes. If you know me, you know how I like this sort of thing.</em>

<em>This post is my take on the first prompt of the book: What Can Happen in a Second? I just wrote without thinking too much about it.</em>

<em>Others might follow. Or not. I haven't read the second prompt yet. I will. But I'm shipping this one first.</em>

[caption id="boat" align="alignright" width="360"]<a href="http://500px.com/photo/11156255"><img class=" wp-image-67 " title="The Patience of a Lonely Boat" src="http://pcdn.500px.net/11156255/cef93067bbb9d90935631a9ddfb7819cf694fd41/4.jpg" alt="A Boat, Shot by Me" width="360" /></a> The Patience of a Lonely Boat, shot by me on an old Nikon FE2 with a fantastic Velvia 50. Doesn't it serve as a good illustration for the slow passage of time?[/caption]

That's an interesting question and not and an easy one to find answers to. It turns out that in our human world, not much can happen in a second. That may be counterintuitive for some. It just sounds right to our ears to hear that some big thing happened in a split second.

It's dramatic.

&nbsp;

- That accident occurred in a split second.

- From one second to the next, everything went from great to chaos.

What's interesting about those examples is that they really are not things that happened in a second. If you stop and think about it, in most cases, an accident had been in gestation for several seconds, minutes, hours, days. Sensationalism and big drama makes us report it otherwise. That, however, can be a rant for some other day.

Let me share this personal story. A story you might know about.

There was this moment last year when my life took a turn. I had received an invitation for a job recruitment event in Montreal for a position on the United States West Coast. I was not really considering relocating but my wife said: "<em>Why not?</em>". Indeed, why not? At that moment, I started steering towards that new path. The horizon opened. You could argue that this change occurred at that second. I disagree. I think I had been contemplating the idea for some time. This idea was far-fetched, unrealistic. But that moment when that question triggered important and new answers was important not in itself, but as a tipping point in a series of events, experiences, reflections.

When I say that not much happens in a second, that's what I'm referring to. There's that decisive moment that breaks the <em>before</em> and <em>after</em> and we're tempted to think it all happened <em>right then</em> but I believe the reality is different.

I'm sure we pass by such moments everyday because we're not in the right mindset (which is quite alright too). As much as big drama seems to feed on split seconds twists, it's often all the little moments that make a big one possible.

So, what can happen in one second? Millions of computations? Several frames in a video? Thousands of tweets? Yes, yes, yes and yes.

But when we’re talking about stories, there’s always more hidden behind that instant of drama.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>99</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-08-08 22:49:20</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-09 05:49:20</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>what-can-happen-in-a-second</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="one-more-thing-to-write-about"><![CDATA[one more thing to write about]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>5</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[New Light on that Blue | Hey it&#039;s Alex!]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://heyitsalex.net/new-light-on-that-blue/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>209.204.175.65</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-08-30 05:22:06</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-08-30 12:22:06</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] Post navigation &larr; Previous [...]]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1346329326.2363";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_as_submitted</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:53:{s:15:"comment_post_ID";s:2:"99";s:14:"comment_author";s:44:"New Light on that Blue | Hey it&#039;s Alex!";s:18:"comment_author_url";s:45:"http://heyitsalex.net/new-light-on-that-blue/";s:20:"comment_author_email";s:0:"";s:15:"comment_content";s:43:"[...] Post navigation &larr; Previous [...]";s:12:"comment_type";s:8:"pingback";s:7:"user_ip";s:14:"209.204.175.65";s:10:"user_agent";s:50:"The Incutio XML-RPC PHP Library -- WordPress/3.4.1";s:8:"referrer";s:0:"";s:4:"blog";s:21:"http://heyitsalex.net";s:9:"blog_lang";s:5:"en_US";s:12:"blog_charset";s:5:"UTF-8";s:9:"permalink";s:50:"http://heyitsalex.net/what-can-happen-in-a-second/";s:21:"akismet_comment_nonce";s:6:"failed";s:15:"SERVER_SOFTWARE";s:70:"Apache/1.3.41 (Unix) mod_auth_pam/1.1.1 FrontPage/5.0.2.2635 PHP/4.4.9";s:11:"REQUEST_URI";s:11:"/xmlrpc.php";s:14:"CONTENT_LENGTH";s:3:"296";s:12:"CONTENT_TYPE";s:8:"text/xml";s:13:"DOCUMENT_ROOT";s:28:"/nfs/WWW-data/support/parked";s:11:"HTTP_ACCEPT";s:3:"*/*";s:20:"HTTP_ACCEPT_ENCODING";s:29:"deflate;q=1.0, compress;q=0.5";s:9:"HTTP_HOST";s:14:"heyitsalex.net";s:25:"HTTP_MOD_SECURITY_MESSAGE";s:94:"Access allowed. Pattern match "/xmlrpc\\.php" at THE_REQUEST [msg "xmlrpc.php post detection"]";s:15:"HTTP_USER_AGENT";s:50:"The Incutio XML-RPC PHP Library -- WordPress/3.4.1";s:4:"PATH";s:44:"/sbin:/usr/sbin:/bin:/usr/bin:/usr/X11R6/bin";s:19:"REDIRECT_SCRIPT_URI";s:32:"http://heyitsalex.net/xmlrpc.php";s:19:"REDIRECT_SCRIPT_URL";s:11:"/xmlrpc.php";s:15:"REDIRECT_STATUS";s:3:"200";s:12:"REDIRECT_URL";s:11:"/xmlrpc.php";s:11:"REMOTE_ADDR";s:14:"209.204.175.65";s:11:"REMOTE_PORT";s:5:"56899";s:15:"SCRIPT_FILENAME";s:58:"/home/WWW_pages/alexandrenormand/heyitsalex.net/xmlrpc.php";s:10:"SCRIPT_URI";s:32:"http://heyitsalex.net/xmlrpc.php";s:10:"SCRIPT_URL";s:11:"/xmlrpc.php";s:11:"SERVER_ADDR";s:14:"209.204.175.65";s:12:"SERVER_ADMIN";s:17:"support@sonic.net";s:11:"SERVER_NAME";s:14:"heyitsalex.net";s:11:"SERVER_PORT";s:2:"80";s:16:"SERVER_SIGNATURE";s:66:"<ADDRESS>Apache/1.3.41 Server at heyitsalex.net Port 80</ADDRESS>
";s:17:"GATEWAY_INTERFACE";s:7:"CGI/1.1";s:15:"SERVER_PROTOCOL";s:8:"HTTP/1.0";s:14:"REQUEST_METHOD";s:4:"POST";s:12:"QUERY_STRING";s:0:"";s:11:"SCRIPT_NAME";s:11:"/xmlrpc.php";s:20:"ORIG_SCRIPT_FILENAME";s:28:"/nfs/www/httpd/cgi-bin/php53";s:14:"ORIG_PATH_INFO";s:11:"/xmlrpc.php";s:20:"ORIG_PATH_TRANSLATED";s:58:"/home/WWW_pages/alexandrenormand/heyitsalex.net/xmlrpc.php";s:16:"ORIG_SCRIPT_NAME";s:14:"/cgi-bin/php53";s:8:"PHP_SELF";s:11:"/xmlrpc.php";s:12:"REQUEST_TIME";s:10:"1346329323";s:4:"argv";s:0:"";s:4:"argc";s:1:"0";s:25:"comment_post_modified_gmt";s:19:"2012-08-09 05:49:20";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New Light on that Blue</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/new-light-on-that-blue/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=125</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>What follows is my take on <a title="What Can Happen in a Second?" href="http://heyitsalex.net/what-can-happen-in-a-second/">another</a> prompt from <a title="642 Things to Write About" href="http://www.amazon.com/Things-Journal-Francisco-Writers-Grotto/dp/1452105448">642 Things to Write About</a>. It's pretty personal, borderline personal diary. Yeah.</em>

<em>Since this blog is my miscellaneous bucket and I'm the editor, I say it's <strong>in</strong>. Let's ship it. Then, see how it feels. </em>

<em>Do not worry, I'm not </em><em>planning on making regular posts about my feelings, probably.   </em>

<em>So here it is, my take on this prompt:  </em>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em></em><em>What a character holding a blue object is thinking about? </em></p>
There I was, holding a blue pen. I had just lost my train of thought. I wasn't exactly looking at it so much as this was an out of focus blue spot. Not any blue either. It was a blue recalling Québec's national blue. I always felt pretty neutral with that particular hue. I always loved blue but I disliked this particular one, much to my chagrin.

Today though, this blue is reminiscent of what we've left behind. We always knew it wouldn't be easy to relocate. The nice things about California are indeed <em>nice</em> but it's not so much like we weren't happy with Montréal. This story isn't one of a quest for the promised land.

[caption id="spellbinding" align="alignright" width="375"]<a href="http://500px.com/photo/12645417"><img title="Spellbinding" src="http://pcdn.500px.net/12645417/0b98f5eab9f13403a48f3489fdc6a8058a985dbc/4.jpg" alt="Spellbinding" width="375" /></a> There's that theme of being somewhere else, shot by me in the Golden Gate Park woods.[/caption]

Some days, we read about cool things that are happening right here, only here. Those days, I feel very fortunate to be here. Other days, we read about some interesting change happening in Montreal and we feel like we're missing out. This is a very typical case of nostalgia versus novelty.

All of that is relatively minor though, in the grand scheme of things.

Everything, except one.

I can do with a slower public transit system.
I can deal with a more complex health care system.
I can accept living in a less lively neighbourhood.
I am however having a real hard time not having friends.

What friends I hear you thinking?

It's true that I didn't have many. I had to make sacrifices when it became obvious that, as a parent, I wouldn't have the time to do all I was doing before. Friendship took second place to personal projects and family.

Except that this is oversimplifying. I still had friends. I was seeing some of them almost exclusively at the office but they <em>were</em> my friends.

I knew it wouldn't be easy to make new friends. I was anticipating that the English speaking version of me would be struggling to find the words to express nuanced thoughts. It would be more difficult to be <em>me</em>.

I knew it would be a challenge.

Is it harder than I thought it would be? Maybe not. But having anticipated it doesn't make it any easier to deal with, that's for sure.

I also very much neglected the difficulty in coordinating talking with friends in Eastern time. We're living in an always connected world after all, aren’t we? It could be easier if I didn't care so much about my work but I <em>do</em>. It's what I came here for and I do love it.

There's no happy revelation here. No words of wisdom. I didn't make a new friend just today that made everything all better.

This is one of those things that will incrementally get better over time. I suppose. I hope.

I'm not sure friends are forever but you could say that we forever needs friends.

Meanwhile, I see this blue pen today and it appears in this newly rediscovered grandiose hue.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>125</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-08-30 03:00:21</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-30 10:00:21</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>new-light-on-that-blue</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="one-more-thing-to-write-about"><![CDATA[one more thing to write about]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>I Still Remember, Even After 6 Months</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/i-still-remember-even-after-6-months/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 05:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=148</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[[caption id="attachment_172" align="alignleft" width="584"]<a href="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/JeMeSouviensVersion2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-172 " title="Je me Souviens" src="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/JeMeSouviensVersion2Landscape-1024x522.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="297" /></a> I remember. Well, at least, what I haven't forgotten.[/caption]

<em>Update: the initial version was way too purple on print. It did look fine on my iPhone screen but the print was definitely not blue, especially when under indoor lights. The guys at gelaskin were kind enough to give me another one for free that I could do with an updated version of the image. This is what you're seeing here. I changed the blue to something that I felt was a safer bet (and better looking to). They looked at it before shipping and they did confirm it looked blue...for real this time.</em>

It's a well-known fact that lack of sunlight affects mood. I know this to be true but it's easy to tell ourselves we're just too strong to feel the influence of something so out of our control as this distant sun.

Except that the sun does help. But the sun is shy in San Francisco during what we conventionally call "summer". Most of the time, the fog is king. Obviously, the closer you get to the coast, the worse it is (or the better it is if you're looking for atmospheric fog).

Then, there's September. People say the fog magically leaves by September. Well, it's a big lie. I've seen some of the thickest fog this September and we barely had any sun. I can't say for sure if it's an anomaly but if someone tells you September is never foggy here, it's a blatant lie. This year was the proof (oh, isn't fun to prove a proposition by a single contradiction?).

Then came October. And now, oh boy, did October deliver. It was great. Not <em>too </em>hot but <em>just</em> right (except for that one time where it was <em>way</em> too hot but that lasted like just one second). Along with the first days of October came the sun and it felt great. You might be like me and love seeing nature's force in action (snowstorms, pouring rain, thunder, thick fog) but we need the sun. I didn't think so much before but I do now.

Then, I remember Montreal. I know, it's been only 6 months or so since we left. You know how it is though. As you leave a place, you start feeling the ties more strongly.

For me, this manifested in an odd manner. I felt like I should show my identity (as if people can't tell from the way I talk). That's a tricky thing. I'm not one to just dress myself with a flag or hang it by the window. But then, there had been this thing I had seen and liked for its looks but didn't really feel right: a <a href="http://www.gelaskins.com/store/phones/iPhone_4/O_Canada">Canadian flag skin</a> for the iPhone. There was also the <a href="http://www.gelaskins.com/store/phones/iPhone_4/Stars_and_Stripes">United States flag</a>, not right either. <a href="http://www.gelaskins.com/store/phones/iPhone_4/Union_Jack">UK flag</a>? Even worse. You can guess the rest of the story.

Oh, you can't? Well, I made my own gelaskin. My Quebec flag gelaskin. I'm not sure I would actually use it if I were still living in Quebec but here? I like the idea. I know I've said in the past that cases and screen protectors are <strong>bad</strong> but I'm making a compromise here. A gelaskin isn't actually a case: it should not add much perceptible thickness to my phone and it's not covering any of the screen.

Like it? Feel free to use <a href="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/JeMeSouviensVersion2.jpg">it</a> to make your own. Or just try it to see how it looks using <a href="http://www.gelaskins.com/create">gelaskin's custom skin creator</a>.

[caption id="attachment_176" align="aligncenter" width="584"]<a href="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/The-Result.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-176" title="The Result" src="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/The-Result-1024x681.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="388" /></a> The Real Thing[/caption]

San Francisco is not Montreal. Talking specifically about weather (yep, this has been my great weather post!), we won't get the great snowstorms of Montreal's winter. That doesn't mean it's always the same though. It might seem like it is sometimes. Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday: same forecast.

Then one day, it's different. One day, there's that pouring rain threatening a Giants game or that thicker fog that completely erases the view. And sometimes, there's the sun and it's rays shinning on through the leaves, bouncing off windows to come and tickle our senses.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>148</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-10-24 22:45:32</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-10-25 05:45:32</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>i-still-remember-even-after-6-months</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="nothing"><![CDATA[nothing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>How Rdio Stole all the Music and Gave it to All of Us </title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/how-rdio-stole-all-the-music-and-gave-it-to-all-of-us/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=166</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[[caption id="attachment_167" align="alignnone" width="350"]<a href="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/DSC_1031.jpg"><img class="wp-image-167 " title="DSC_1031" alt="" src="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/DSC_1031-1024x682.jpg" width="350" height="233" /></a> My old days of listening to music.[/caption]
<blockquote>“We've got all you music. Surrender a fee and it's yours.”</blockquote>
This sounds like a ransom note from a villain. It's not. This is the promise of music services like <a href="http://rdio.com/">Rdio</a> and <a href="http://www.spotify.com/">Spotify</a>.

And it's great.

I remember feeling hesitant when the digital age began. I liked putting my favourite albums on display. After some time, I realized that I never actually looked at them and it was just more <em>stuff</em> to carry around. I slowly stopped buying physical CDs. This was liberating.

Then came the iTunes age. I would buy albums and store them in a nice folder that kept growing. Backed up with <a href="http://www.backblaze.com/">Backblaze</a> too. However, I now look at some of this music and I've either listened it to death or I've changed my mind about it. In all cases, most of the time, I just listen to the more recent great stuff.

That last part has been a problem for me in the last few years. You know how it is. When you become a dad, you've got less free time. I know some dads that are still up-to-date on the latest great music but I think you've got only a few picks to make when you've got less free time. I chose photography and software. I had to give up on music. Thankfully, some of the bands I was listening to are still doing some innovative work so I wasn't  <em>completely </em>out.

When I moved this year, I also decided to try to get back into it a bit more. Ideally without having to put too much time into it. My priorities hadn't changed. I tried <a href="http://www.spotify.com/">Spotify</a> and <a href="http://www.pandora.com/">Pandora</a>. I didn't have such a good experience with <a href="http://www.spotify.com/">Spotify</a>. Even though I had access to a huge selection, I just didn't know what to look for. <a href="http://www.pandora.com/">Pandora</a> was definitely better in that regard. I could use something I knew as a reference and get a radio station with potentially good picks. That was unsatisfying to me though. When you stumble on a great track and want to listen to more of that band, you're left on your own.

Enter <a href="http://rdio.com/">Rdio</a>. After reading good words about it, I decided give the trial a try. I liked it. I still do.

Specifically, I had access to playlists that were a great starting point (like pitchfork's best songs). Then, as I discovered things I liked, I could add bands and albums to my collection and even synchronize them to my iPhone.

And that's all I need.

Easy discovery with trusted curated content and access to an exhaustive music library. Sure, I have to pay every month. But, one month of <a href="http://rdio.com/">Rdio</a> is the price of a single album on iTunes. Yes, I lose it all if I decide to cancel. When you think about it though, that music I was listening to a few months ago isn't really what I'm going to want to listen to in two months anyway. Also, if I were to find another solution, I'll probably have the same music there anyway. And if not, that's fine too.

The really cool thing about all of this though goes beyond easy access to music: No more <em>stuff</em>. Nothing to carry around. This is definitely more liberating that the jump to the digital age. This is acknowledging that we change and we might not have to keep all of our things from the past with us because we cherished it at some point.

I still have stuff I'm carrying along with me, way <em>too</em> much. I know. Hopefully though, this stuff is now more of my own creations (or my creation tools) than stuff I acquire. Not ideal, but better.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>166</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-11-04 21:04:52</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-11-05 05:04:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>how-rdio-stole-all-the-music-and-gave-it-to-all-of-us</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="nothing"><![CDATA[nothing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_category</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[text]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_hidden</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_customurl</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_language</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[en_GB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>6</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Before Buying Fences &#8211; 3 Important Tips&nbsp;|&nbsp;ftm-forum.com]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://ftm-forum.com/before-buying-fences-3-important-tips/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>129.121.129.121</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-12-05 16:59:13</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-12-06 00:59:13</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] 3 Important Tips For The New Sales Person8 Important Tips For Working With A Special Needs ChildFive Important Tips on Gambling Income and LossesDIY Woven Chain Bracelet &#8211; Honestly WTFDrug Smugglers Breach Arizona Border Fence &#8211; With a Car Jack!Dealing With An Abrasive Bosslongchampï¼Œlancelï¼Œvanessa bruno sont connues pour ses sac Ã  main Ã  la mode avec un design spÃ©cial.Proper On-site Search Engine Optimization Is Good For Ranking When You Build Up Hundreds Of Thousands Of Pages Over Time!How Rdio Stole all the Music and Gave it to All of Us [...]]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Love Letter to Github</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/love-letter-to-github/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=179</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[[caption id="attachment_181" align="alignright" width="246"]<a href="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Octocalex-2012-12-16-07.49.31-168-PM1.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-181" alt="I'm really sorry about this. I wanted an image and I thought drawing myself octocat-style would be cool. I guess it could have if I had done a better job. For the record, I blame the tools. No SketchBook Ink for me next time. " src="http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Octocalex-2012-12-16-07.49.31-168-PM1-246x300.png" width="246" height="300" /></a> I'm really sorry about this. I wanted an image and I thought drawing myself octocat-style would be cool. I guess it could have been if I had done a better job. For the record, I blame the tools. No SketchBook Ink for me next time.[/caption]

I have one thing I want to say today: I love <a href="https://github.com/">Github</a>.

Since this would just barely be worthy of a tiny tweet (and not even a <em>good</em> one), I'm going to stretch this as far as I can to get to a blog post length. Just because I feel like blogging today. Yes, that's just how it's going to be.

The past week was really great. Don't you care to know why? Well, fine, I'm telling anyway.

It starts with me just trying to get some data on the distribution of the data across regions in hbase. I thought it was something we should be looking at.

Enters <a href="https://github.com/sentric/hannibal">Hannibal</a>.

In a few minutes, I had cloned it, built it and had it running against one of our clusters. The visuals are really good and it definitely increases our ability to quickly see where we're at compared to a text output (which can also be done pretty easily with an hbase shell script).

With this running instance on our data quickly came the realization that we'd use this for real. And, like, <em>right now</em>.

On closer look, I noticed issues with getting compaction logs. Also, I started thinking of some things we might tweak to make it easier to have this deployed and running internally.

I'm not going to go into the details of the changes involved. The <strong>process</strong> is really the topic I had in mind when sitting down to write this. Or rather the lack thereof really.

Did you notice? I just lied straight to your face and I knew you wouldn't budge. Actually, there <em>is</em> a process but Github makes it all so easy and fun that it doesn't feel like the drag we so often associate with processes.

Here's how this lays out: You read about this thing or google your way to it. You need this thing and someone already wrote it. It starts here and then...
<ol>
	<li>Clone, build, run and use the thing.</li>
	<li>There's something missing or that could use some improvement.</li>
	<li>You feel the urge to fix it.</li>
</ol>
That's the critical part right there. It's often where things <em>get complicated</em>. You might need to file a ticket first with steps to reproduce. You might need to sell people of that feature you think <em>should definitely</em> be in the scope of the project. You know, it's complicated™. But Github helps. Let's get on with how this goes with it...
<ol start="4">
	<li>You fork it. A one click step.</li>
	<li>You do the work. And it's the most fun part. You're excited because this is something that bugged <em>you</em>. It's something <em>you</em> care about.</li>
	<li>Done with the changes? Now it's pull requesta extravaganza! This is when you get to show off the interesting work you've cared so much about. Also, because it's cool to work with people excited about your project, interesting discussions follow. Meeting new folks. You know, <em>talking</em> (or, more accurately, <em>typing</em>).</li>
	<li>I'm just describing one scenario here but let's say everything is right and your changes were merged into the upstream repo. Doesn't this feel <em>great</em>? It's almost silly but I just feel like a little boy and I want to show mommy how proud I am of the thing I just did. Even for a one line change. I'd like to show the whole world about this thing I just did. Please refrain though. People will run away screaming if you do this too often. And maybe even the first time you do it. So, please, don't!</li>
	<li>You just feel like smiling.</li>
</ol>
To be fair, you can get the same great rewarding feeling from contributing to any open source project even if that's not hosted on <a href="https://github.com/">Github</a>. But the entry barrier is just a little bit higher. It takes more time. Some of that precious and limited energy that you have is spent on the <em>other</em> stuff that, well, isn't as much fun.

Anything to make the process so easy it just seems to <em>not</em> exist is an amazing feat. <a href="https://github.com/">Github</a> really enables tons of changes (okay, I just made that up but I really think it's a good uneducated guess) by just making a path available from discovering a personal need to getting it done. Github is empowering people to fix it <em>immediately</em>. And we all know how momentum is important.

I think I won't shock anyone if I say we wouldn't want to go back to a world without <a href="https://github.com/">Github</a>. More than <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/">JetBrains</a>, Github really brings the <em>develop with pleasure</em> motto to life.

Dear Github, I love you. Never leave me.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>179</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-12-16 22:07:09</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-12-17 06:07:09</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>love-letter-to-github</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="nothing"><![CDATA[nothing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_all</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_category</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[text]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_hidden</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_customurl</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Juxtapose</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/juxtapose/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 05:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=205</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[A few weeks ago, I came across some stunning <a href="http://imgur.com/a/wxBBm#0">compositing work</a> from <a href="http://realcalvinandhobbes.tumblr.com/">Michael Den Beste</a>. The project juxtaposes drawings of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calvin_and_Hobbes">Calvin and Hobbes</a> with fitting nature photographs.

By themselves, the photos would be pretty good albeit lacking a distinguishing element. With Calvin and Hobbes, the scene comes alive. The drawings bring a touch of imagination in an otherwise very real scene. I felt as if the world was being filled with mystical creatures from storybooks. It's breaking the monotony of a thousand pretty pictures while celebrating of the beauty of nature.

You can tell I felt inspired by that work. I also happen to take random unpublished pictures suited for such compositing work: <em>wallpaper-nice</em> caliber but nothing crazy unique. I also happen to draw things. Or, I try to. Here is my first attempt at this type of composite art. It's an old pouring rain picture that I augmented with my drawing of a snail. I have much better photos in reserve for this type of work but this one seemed to be fitting with my character so I'm going with that. Uncharacteristically for me, this won't be a scheduled project. But, I'll make more.

[caption align="aligncenter" width="480"]<a href="http://flickr.com/gp/alexnormand/0xeDzc" title="Freaktargos by skippyjon"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8234/8508412905_e34d5b1429_b.jpg" width="480" height="480" alt="Freaktargos"></a> This is it.[/caption]

<div id="list1">
   <p>Technical details:</p>
   <ul>
      <li><p>Original picture processed with Aperture, exported via Dropbox to iPad.</p></li>
      <li><p>I drew the a low-resolution version of the snail with <a href="http://www.fiftythree.com/paper">Paper</a> on the iPad and my <a href="http://www.tenonedesign.com/connect.php">Pogo Connect</a></p></li>
      <li><p>Then, I exported to <a href="http://www.procreate.si/">Procreate</a> and used it as the basis for a higher resolution and full color version.</p></li>
      <li><p>Composited the photo and drawing in Procreate.</p></li>
      <li><p>That output was then tweaked with snapseed for drama and then <a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop-touch.html">Photoshop Touch</a> to add the horizontal black border.</p></li>
   </ul>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>205</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-02-27 21:58:53</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-02-28 05:58:53</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>juxtapose</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="calvinball-project"><![CDATA[calvinball project]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_hidden</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_customurl</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_all</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Entertain with your Big Data</title>
		<link>http://heyitsalex.net/entertain-with-your-big-data/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 20:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexandre.normand</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://heyitsalex.net/?p=260</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[So, you've got this big, smart, scalable and just plain awesome infrastructure that you're building. It's the key to everything™. It's therefore very natural for you to feel proud of all the work. You want to very passionately talk about how it all works. You might want to tell the tale of all the clever things you've had to do.

Except that you don't always have people's attention. We don't always have infinite time. Sometimes, you only have 2 minutes to talk. And sometimes, people like to be entertained.
Actually, people always like to be entertained. And you can only show so much. Words are interesting but pictures are more entertaining.

What are you left with when the product of your work doesn't have a UI? What is your mother going to say when she sees the bytes from your scan of million of rows in hbase?* At Opower, we have what we call demo days. Each quarter, we have one big demo where all the teams present a demo of what they've been up to during the last quarter. For this last quarter, we decided to make something easier for the audience (look ma', no more terminal!). Let's go through some of the ideas that were discussed:
<ul>
	<li>
<ol>Record timelapses of hannibal showing data getting loaded in our tables.</ol>
<ol>Timelapse of clstrfck (an internal tool built during innovation day, it displays jobs running on hadoop visually).</ol>
</li>
</ul>
Those were good ideas but they involved tooling challenges (how do we record time-lapses of multiple web visualizations and then combine them for the demo?). The solution was obvious: grab all the data while the test was running and build the visualization to play back the test run. What? Back-end software engineers doing javascript? It did sound too much work initially but after a short denial/acceptance phase and some research, I decided to give that a try helped by a good <a href="http://bost.ocks.org/mike/nations/">d3.js motion chart example</a> from which we could reuse much of the same patterns.

Result? An 2 minutes time-lapse showing the data being added to our hbase tables (which would have been hannibal's role) overlaid with visualization of the hadoop jobs running (clstrfck's role). Yes, it violates a <a href="http://www2.cs.uregina.ca/~rbm/cs100/notes/spreadsheets/tufte_paper.html">few rules of information display</a>. Ok, it violates several of those rules. As we everything, we have to pick what to optimize for. First was the deadline: we had to have something ready in time for the demo day and the test that was going to be played back in accelerated was in the order of a few days to complete. Second in the list was maximum entertainment and getting people's attention. We thought that if people liked it enough, they would engage in conversations following the demo and we could get into more details.

The demo
I know you want to see it so here it is. Get your popcorn and enjoy the entertainment. You might have questions about what's actually going on there. Or if you don't, you can have a look at the slower time-lapse running directly in your browser. If you do have questions, leave a comment and someone* will answer.

One last thing before you hit play: we haven't won any Oscars (yet) but we did win the prestigious "Best demo" awards during our demo day. I'd like to thank all the team for tolerating my excesses during that week preceding the demo. I'd like to thank Eric for presenting it (and providing some very valuable feedback on what to leave out of the demo), Kenny and Oren for the voice acting, Yoni for all the critics when I actually just wanted a little help on this tiny javascript detail and Scott for assisting in driving the 49 hours test.

Without broadcasting all of our team's internal culture, we have a recurring Keanu Reeves theme in our projects. You'll notice a lot of that in the video
* Actually, I'd be interested in seeing that. My mother lives very far so if you guys want to try it, please post a youtube reaction video link in the comments.
* Probably me.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>260</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-07-13 13:05:29</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-07-13 20:05:29</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>entertain-with-your-big-data</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>trash</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_customurl</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_flattr_post_hidden</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_trash_meta_time</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1374287261]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_trash_meta_status</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[draft]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
