<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Photography on  </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.heyitsalex.net/categories/photography/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 04:30:35 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tourist Photographer&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>http://www.heyitsalex.net/the-tourist-photographers-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 04:30:35 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heyitsalex.net/the-tourist-photographers-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wholeheartedly loathe tourist photos. I really do. I get angry just thinking about it. I really really hate this. Let me go outside and throw some rocks on a concrete wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I&amp;rsquo;m back (I actually just grabbed a snack instead).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me first explain what I think is the problem with tourist photos: they&amp;rsquo;re just too much. It&amp;rsquo;s all inclusive. It has you, your kids, all of your magnificent landmark and it&amp;rsquo;s surroundings. That kind of thing &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; works. Cameras should just pretend to be out of battery when faced with such a scene (they can recognizes &lt;em&gt;faces&lt;/em&gt; already so that&amp;rsquo;s possible right?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7423/9349733524_71036a6a7c_h_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        This is a Boston landmark picture subtly showcasing the family. I&amp;#39;m not terribly proud of it but I don&amp;#39;t need to hide when people ask if I took it (I mean, if I were to hide, it would not be because of that).
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work is simple: a picture that has more than _one_ thing makes that one thing much more difficult to stand out. We all have different tastes and opinions. As such, you might disagree but let&amp;rsquo;s just stop for a minute to look at pictures we like (I&amp;rsquo;ll go do something better while you take a few moments and do it). I think you&amp;rsquo;ll find that those are recurring patterns: shallow depth of field, uncoloured backgrounds, isolated subject, sharp focus. All of them have the same effect: make _one_ single thing stand out. Even ultra wide angles that seem to capture all of the surroundings produce great images when their focus is on making one thing stand out: the perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tourist photos are sickening because they do all the opposite. They cram people faking smiles on top of a very busy landmark scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we&amp;rsquo;re faced with this dilemma as photographers _and_ tourists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refuse to take the tourist snapshots and just take time to focus on quality work while pissing off everyone in the group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take the snapshots the best you can with your big camera to take the touristy snapshots with better execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m actually not sure we can resolve this to the satisfaction of everyone involved (unless you&amp;rsquo;re a family of photographers) but with a little effort, we can at least make an attempt. Or I tell you how and &lt;em&gt;you_ make the attempt. Just kidding, I&amp;rsquo;m not letting _you&lt;/em&gt; try this alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s try and make tourist pictures better. First, let&amp;rsquo;s forget about showing off that you &lt;em&gt;were there in front of the golden bridge, omg!!&lt;/em&gt; People are doing it everyday and you can just tweet it, we&amp;rsquo;ll believe it. If we want to see the golden gate, we can google it and find fabulous shots that have been taken a thousand times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexnormand/4829260124/in/set-72157624547713078/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4136/4829260124_57712e570a_o_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        One of my favorite touristy-type photos. I secretly waited for the good light while we were having fun and took this. Only regret: a stupid pole in the top-left corner of the frame I had to clumsily get rid of at post-processing.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not against using a landmark (or part of it) if it makes for a good picture though. A kid holding a coloured umbrella walking out of the fog on the golden gate bridge would be magnificent (I should do that shot before I start to think of the potential challenges involved). Let&amp;rsquo;s just forget about taking pictures of you and ALL of that gigantic scene. Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on isolated things. If you must take a picture with the statue of a president, make it a close up of yourself French kissing it. Want to capture yourself with the beautiful Apple store? Take a close shot of a reflection in it&amp;rsquo;s recognizable glass walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your job as the photographer (I know, it&amp;rsquo;s not your job, it&amp;rsquo;s just a hobby) is showing one interesting thing and removing everything else that gets in the way. Or at least, it&amp;rsquo;s a big part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well enough talk, now let&amp;rsquo;s try this. Don&amp;rsquo;t wait to be on vacation. Next time you&amp;rsquo;re outside, go play tourist in your own hometown. That&amp;rsquo;s something we always neglect anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe keep a &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; happy snapshots along the way as a peace offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just in case.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>