<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Nothing on  </title>
    <link>http://heyitsalex.net/tags/nothing/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Alexandre Normand</author>
    <rights>Licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported License by Alexandre Normand</rights>
    <updated>2012-12-17 06:07:09 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter to Github</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/love-letter-to-github</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:07:09 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <author>Alexandre Normand</author>
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/love-letter-to-github</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;medium&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Octocalex-2012-12-16-07.49.31-168-PM1.png&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        I&amp;#39;m really sorry about this. I wanted an image and I thought drawing myself octocat-style would be cool. I guess it could have been if I had done a better job. For the record, I blame the tools. No SketchBook Ink for me next time.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have one thing I want to say today: I love &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this would just barely be worthy of a tiny tweet (and not even a _good_ one), I&amp;rsquo;m going to stretch this as far as I can to get to a blog post length. Just because I feel like blogging today. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s just how it&amp;rsquo;s going to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past week was really great. Don&amp;rsquo;t you care to know why? Well, fine, I&amp;rsquo;m telling anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with me just trying to get some data on the distribution of the data across regions in hbase. I thought it was something we should be looking at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enters &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sentric/hannibal&#34;&gt;Hannibal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a few minutes, I had cloned it, built it and had it running against one of our clusters. The visuals are really good and it definitely increases our ability to quickly see where we&amp;rsquo;re at compared to a text output (which can also be done pretty easily with an hbase shell script).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this running instance on our data quickly came the realization that we&amp;rsquo;d use this for real. And, like, &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On closer look, I noticed issues with getting compaction logs. Also, I started thinking of some things we might tweak to make it easier to have this deployed and running internally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into the details of the changes involved. The &lt;strong&gt;process&lt;/strong&gt; is really the topic I had in mind when sitting down to write this. Or rather the lack thereof really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you notice? I just lied straight to your face and I knew you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t budge. Actually, there _is_ a process but Github makes it all so easy and fun that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like the drag we so often associate with processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how this lays out: You read about this thing or google your way to it. You need this thing and someone already wrote it. It starts here and then&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clone, build, run and use the thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something missing or that could use some improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You feel the urge to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the critical part right there. It&amp;rsquo;s often where things &lt;em&gt;get complicated&lt;/em&gt;. You might need to file a ticket first with steps to reproduce. You might need to sell people of that feature you think _should definitely_ be in the scope of the project. You know, it&amp;rsquo;s complicated™. But Github helps. Let&amp;rsquo;s get on with how this goes with it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You fork it. A one click step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You do the work. And it&amp;rsquo;s the most fun part. You&amp;rsquo;re excited because this is something that bugged &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s something _you_ care about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Done with the changes? Now it&amp;rsquo;s pull requesta extravaganza! This is when you get to show off the interesting work you&amp;rsquo;ve cared so much about. Also, because it&amp;rsquo;s cool to work with people excited about your project, interesting discussions follow. Meeting new folks. You know, &lt;em&gt;talking_ (or, more accurately, _typing&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just describing one scenario here but let&amp;rsquo;s say everything is right and your changes were merged into the upstream repo. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this feel &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;? It&amp;rsquo;s almost silly but I just feel like a little boy and I want to show mommy how proud I am of the thing I just did. Even for a one line change. I&amp;rsquo;d like to show the whole world about this thing I just did. Please refrain though. People will run away screaming if you do this too often. And maybe even the first time you do it. So, please, don&amp;rsquo;t!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You just feel like smiling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, you can get the same great rewarding feeling from contributing to any open source project even if that&amp;rsquo;s not hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. But the entry barrier is just a little bit higher. It takes more time. Some of that precious and limited energy that you have is spent on the _other_ stuff that, well, isn&amp;rsquo;t as much fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything to make the process so easy it just seems to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; exist is an amazing feat. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; really enables tons of changes (okay, I just made that up but I really think it&amp;rsquo;s a good uneducated guess) by just making a path available from discovering a personal need to getting it done. Github is empowering people to fix it &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt;. And we all know how momentum is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I won&amp;rsquo;t shock anyone if I say we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to go back to a world without &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. More than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/&#34;&gt;JetBrains&lt;/a&gt;, Github really brings the _develop with pleasure_ motto to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Github, I love you. Never leave me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rdio Stole all the Music and Gave it to All of Us </title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/how-rdio-stole-all-the-music-and-gave-it-to-all-of-us</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 05:04:52 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <author>Alexandre Normand</author>
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/how-rdio-stole-all-the-music-and-gave-it-to-all-of-us</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/DSC_1031-1024x682.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        My old days of listening to music.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We&amp;rsquo;ve got all you music. Surrender a fee and it&amp;rsquo;s yours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds like a ransom note from a villain. It&amp;rsquo;s not. This is the promise of music services like &lt;a href=&#34;http://rdio.com/&#34;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spotify.com/&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember feeling hesitant when the digital age began. I liked putting my favourite albums on display. After some time, I realized that I never actually looked at them and it was just more _stuff_ to carry around. I slowly stopped buying physical CDs. This was liberating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the iTunes age. I would buy albums and store them in a nice folder that kept growing. Backed up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com/&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt; too. However, I now look at some of this music and I&amp;rsquo;ve either listened it to death or I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my mind about it. In all cases, most of the time, I just listen to the more recent great stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last part has been a problem for me in the last few years. You know how it is. When you become a dad, you&amp;rsquo;ve got less free time. I know some dads that are still up-to-date on the latest great music but I think you&amp;rsquo;ve got only a few picks to make when you&amp;rsquo;ve got less free time. I chose photography and software. I had to give up on music. Thankfully, some of the bands I was listening to are still doing some innovative work so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t  _completely _out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I moved this year, I also decided to try to get back into it a bit more. Ideally without having to put too much time into it. My priorities hadn&amp;rsquo;t changed. I tried &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spotify.com/&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pandora.com/&#34;&gt;Pandora&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have such a good experience with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spotify.com/&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;. Even though I had access to a huge selection, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to look for. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pandora.com/&#34;&gt;Pandora&lt;/a&gt; was definitely better in that regard. I could use something I knew as a reference and get a radio station with potentially good picks. That was unsatisfying to me though. When you stumble on a great track and want to listen to more of that band, you&amp;rsquo;re left on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;http://rdio.com/&#34;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt;. After reading good words about it, I decided give the trial a try. I liked it. I still do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I had access to playlists that were a great starting point (like pitchfork&amp;rsquo;s best songs). Then, as I discovered things I liked, I could add bands and albums to my collection and even synchronize them to my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s all I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy discovery with trusted curated content and access to an exhaustive music library. Sure, I have to pay every month. But, one month of &lt;a href=&#34;http://rdio.com/&#34;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt; is the price of a single album on iTunes. Yes, I lose it all if I decide to cancel. When you think about it though, that music I was listening to a few months ago isn&amp;rsquo;t really what I&amp;rsquo;m going to want to listen to in two months anyway. Also, if I were to find another solution, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have the same music there anyway. And if not, that&amp;rsquo;s fine too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really cool thing about all of this though goes beyond easy access to music: No more &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;. Nothing to carry around. This is definitely more liberating that the jump to the digital age. This is acknowledging that we change and we might not have to keep all of our things from the past with us because we cherished it at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have stuff I&amp;rsquo;m carrying along with me, way _too_ much. I know. Hopefully though, this stuff is now more of my own creations (or my creation tools) than stuff I acquire. Not ideal, but better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Still Remember, Even After 6 Months</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/i-still-remember-even-after-6-months</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 05:45:32 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <author>Alexandre Normand</author>
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/i-still-remember-even-after-6-months</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/JeMeSouviensVersion2Landscape-1024x522.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        I remember. Well, at least, what I haven&amp;#39;t forgotten.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: the initial version was way too purple on print. It did look fine on my iPhone screen but the print was definitely not blue, especially when under indoor lights. The guys at gelaskin were kind enough to give me another one for free that I could do with an updated version of the image. This is what you&amp;rsquo;re seeing here. I changed the blue to something that I felt was a safer bet (and better looking to). They looked at it before shipping and they did confirm it looked blue&amp;hellip;for real this time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a well-known fact that lack of sunlight affects mood. I know this to be true but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to tell ourselves we&amp;rsquo;re just too strong to feel the influence of something so out of our control as this distant sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except that the sun does help. But the sun is shy in San Francisco during what we conventionally call &amp;ldquo;summer&amp;rdquo;. Most of the time, the fog is king. Obviously, the closer you get to the coast, the worse it is (or the better it is if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for atmospheric fog).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, there&amp;rsquo;s September. People say the fog magically leaves by September. Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a big lie. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some of the thickest fog this September and we barely had any sun. I can&amp;rsquo;t say for sure if it&amp;rsquo;s an anomaly but if someone tells you September is never foggy here, it&amp;rsquo;s a blatant lie. This year was the proof (oh, isn&amp;rsquo;t fun to prove a proposition by a single contradiction?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came October. And now, oh boy, did October deliver. It was great. Not &lt;em&gt;too _hot but _just&lt;/em&gt; right (except for that one time where it was &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too hot but that lasted like just one second). Along with the first days of October came the sun and it felt great. You might be like me and love seeing nature&amp;rsquo;s force in action (snowstorms, pouring rain, thunder, thick fog) but we need the sun. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think so much before but I do now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I remember Montreal. I know, it&amp;rsquo;s been only 6 months or so since we left. You know how it is though. As you leave a place, you start feeling the ties more strongly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this manifested in an odd manner. I felt like I should show my identity (as if people can&amp;rsquo;t tell from the way I talk). That&amp;rsquo;s a tricky thing. I&amp;rsquo;m not one to just dress myself with a flag or hang it by the window. But then, there had been this thing I had seen and liked for its looks but didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel right: a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gelaskins.com/store/phones/iPhone_4/O_Canada&#34;&gt;Canadian flag skin&lt;/a&gt; for the iPhone. There was also the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gelaskins.com/store/phones/iPhone_4/Stars_and_Stripes&#34;&gt;United States flag&lt;/a&gt;, not right either. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gelaskins.com/store/phones/iPhone_4/Union_Jack&#34;&gt;UK flag&lt;/a&gt;? Even worse. You can guess the rest of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, you can&amp;rsquo;t? Well, I made my own gelaskin. My Quebec flag gelaskin. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I would actually use it if I were still living in Quebec but here? I like the idea. I know I&amp;rsquo;ve said in the past that cases and screen protectors are &lt;strong&gt;bad&lt;/strong&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;m making a compromise here. A gelaskin isn&amp;rsquo;t actually a case: it should not add much perceptible thickness to my phone and it&amp;rsquo;s not covering any of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like it? Feel free to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/JeMeSouviensVersion2.jpg&#34;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt; to make your own. Or just try it to see how it looks using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gelaskins.com/create&#34;&gt;gelaskin&amp;rsquo;s custom skin creator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/The-Result-1024x681.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        The Real Thing.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;San Francisco is not Montreal. Talking specifically about weather (yep, this has been my great weather post!), we won&amp;rsquo;t get the great snowstorms of Montreal&amp;rsquo;s winter. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s always the same though. It might seem like it is sometimes. Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday: same forecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one day, it&amp;rsquo;s different. One day, there&amp;rsquo;s that pouring rain threatening a Giants game or that thicker fog that completely erases the view. And sometimes, there&amp;rsquo;s the sun and it&amp;rsquo;s rays shinning on through the leaves, bouncing off windows to come and tickle our senses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Almost Everything [or Nothing]</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-ultimate-guide-to-almost-everything-or-nothing</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 05:05:49 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <author>Alexandre Normand</author>
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/the-ultimate-guide-to-almost-everything-or-nothing</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: After finishing and reading this post (ok, I &lt;em&gt;skimmed&lt;/em&gt; through it), I updated the title to better reflect its content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is going to be one of those serious posts where I tell know how to live your life to &amp;ldquo;enlarge&amp;rdquo; your happiness. This is all going to be bulletproof advice that I may or may not follow myself (but really, &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; me, I&amp;rsquo;m just putting that disclaimer there to please lawyers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On second thought (ok, on &lt;em&gt;initial&lt;/em&gt; thought, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really did any thinking before writing this out), scratch that, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to tell you how to live your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am, however, going to tell you &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;precisely&lt;/em&gt; how to do &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done research, experimentation and just plain thinking (transit time equals free thinking time) over the course of the last few years. I&amp;rsquo;m not putting any references here but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;just say things&lt;/em&gt; so, trust me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve come to believe is that the key to doing great work consistently lies in two elementary rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&#34;&gt;The Seinfeld Chain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/calendar167d36622f4559b122840489a4b456b59efb1581.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        My Calendar for July, a Really Bad Example of a Seinfeld Chain Illustration Because it&amp;#39;s Empty since the Month Hasn&amp;#39;t started Yet.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be daily but you should have a schedule with outputs and you should stick to it. Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re just a slacker constantly putting off tasks, that won&amp;rsquo;t help. You might get some things done once in a while but your chain will look like a bunch of stupid rings. You will look at this and think back at this &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&#34;&gt;Seinfeld chain&lt;/a&gt; and since your efforts are so pathetic, you&amp;rsquo;ll just give up and never get anything done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, now that we got rid of the self conscious slackers, let&amp;rsquo;s get to the second point&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;2. Don&amp;rsquo;t overwork. Do work and celebrate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is pretty intuitive really. You get some good work done and you enjoy the satisfaction. That&amp;rsquo;s it. When you do that, you&amp;rsquo;ve got something to be proud of and something to look forward to for next time. Now, you rest or just do something else. If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, you&amp;rsquo;re currently in leisure mode so get ready and go back to work (but finish reading first).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we feel like just going on a continuous non stopped stretch is just the structure of work life. Work more, get more done, &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3180-a-good-days-work&#34;&gt;right&lt;/a&gt;? Well, as much as we would like this to be true, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be generally the case. It&amp;rsquo;s less easy to apply this to a 40 hours job where work time is crucial. Don&amp;rsquo;t go using that as an excuse though. If you learn to split tasks into smaller tasks, then it is possible to eventually get to a point when you can leave work everyday having accomplished stuff and feeling good about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, that last part was pretty dry but it&amp;rsquo;s the key to something so it had to be said (and read, I really hope you read it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time, stay curious and don&amp;rsquo;t let you phone run out of battery (unrelated advice but it&amp;rsquo;s really not cool if someone needs to call you and you can&amp;rsquo;t get the call).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coming next: how to master a second language as a grown-up?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(okay, it won&amp;rsquo;t be my next post, it&amp;rsquo;s more of an actual question from me to the world! I don&amp;rsquo;t know how, I&amp;rsquo;m so horrendously horrible at this).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The San Francisco Guide for Montréalers</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/the-san-francisco-guide-for-montrealers</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 05:00:55 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <author>Alexandre Normand</author>
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/the-san-francisco-guide-for-montrealers</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You dear reader should already know that I&amp;rsquo;m a new San Franciscan and ex-Montréaler. As such, I present you with great authority the definite guide to San Francisco for Montréalers. It&amp;rsquo;s really more of a collection of fairly obvious differences between Montréal and San Francisco. I really rely on my blog getting zero readership to shield me from real potential of offending residents of both cities. It may have been better titled as &amp;ldquo;10 differences between Montréal and San Francisco&amp;rdquo; but I hate those. They most often come in round numbers which I find suspicious. How convenient would it be if there were really 10 differences between the two cities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering this, I&amp;rsquo;m not even counting how many I&amp;rsquo;m listing here. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that to you and I might just trick you and update this list (hey, this could be a living document). The following represent my opinions but I believe it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say most with the same background as me would agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;STM Kicks Ass and Muni not so Much&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t know what you have until you lose it, right? Actually, I knew the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.examiner.com/article/stm-wins-the-stanley-cup-of-public-transport-for-north-america&#34;&gt;STM was pretty good&lt;/a&gt;. But after seeing tramways, BART and buses in movies depicting San Francisco, I thought the public transport here would be amazing. It&amp;rsquo;s not really. Muni is cheaper but it&amp;rsquo;s also as slow as it is unreliable. To be fair, it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely a problem of Muni but rather a problem with traffic and lack of speedy ways reserved for buses. Express buses are not really &lt;em&gt;express&lt;/em&gt;. Additionally if you have a positively surprising experience with an express bus one day, Muni will make sure to make it up the next day with the express just flying by your stop with a bus fully packed of people. Yes, leaving you, the hopeful commuter, standing there feeling the chilly wind crushing your hopes of a quick transit and the seed of cynicism growing inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there are also little details like no sign whatsoever for Express buses stops on Pine street. There are several express routes stopping here and you don&amp;rsquo;t have any way of telling which will stop where. Apparently it&amp;rsquo;s knowledge that gets passed from &lt;em&gt;generation to generation&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told it&amp;rsquo;s in somewhat numerical ordering by some wise guy who seemed to have reversed engineered it. Still haven&amp;rsquo;t verified it. I just memorized the address of the building where the 31AX stops (for the record, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://maps.google.com/maps?q=360+pine+st,+San+francisco&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ll=37.791558,-122.401353&amp;amp;spn=0.006249,0.013937&amp;amp;sll=37.792069,-122.402002&amp;amp;layer=c&amp;amp;cbp=13,16.36,,0,0.05&amp;amp;cbll=37.791962,-122.40204&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;hnear=360+Pine+St,+San+Francisco,+California+94104&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;z=17&amp;amp;iwloc=A&amp;amp;panoid=7CHnHdxivs7YOWxItuJU8Q&#34;&gt;360 Pine St&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;The SF Bus Drivers All Hate Life, Montréal Drivers Actually Enjoy Driving People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true. You may want to be polite or friendly and salute your driver when you enter or thank him/her when you get off but you&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised to get a smile or even an answer back. STM drivers will generally welcome everyone on board and salute them when they get off. I had drivers recognize me and talk to me just like that (remember, I am not good with people!). I even had one watch for me arriving to the stop from the other side of the street to signal me to wait and not cross foolishly when it wasn&amp;rsquo;t safe as he proceeded to wait for the light change and get me on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that&amp;rsquo;s not enough, here&amp;rsquo;s a true STM story: there&amp;rsquo;s a driver that sings the name of bus stops every morning. I have never actually seen it myself but the tellings are true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, some Montreal drivers (but those are in the minority) aren&amp;rsquo;t that friendly. Also, I said all muni drivers hate life and all living creatures on earth but I rode the 31 one evening and the driver was the nicest, going as far as &lt;em&gt;fist bumping&lt;/em&gt; me as I got off the bus (this made my day, I love this guy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;All People You See in SF are not Attractive, Montréal Wins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really surprising. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;m married and it&amp;rsquo;s not like I&amp;rsquo;m here looking around but living in the city, you see people everyday. You sort of subconsciously assess the beauty of the population around you, I guess. There&amp;rsquo;s probably someone studying that social behavior but I&amp;rsquo;m just there to tell you that the truth is this: it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to make your way to work and back without seeing someone really good looking. Maybe my sample doesn&amp;rsquo;t accurately reflect the larger population of san Francisco, I mostly see people riding muni (could this explain why muni drivers have those gloomy eyes?) but there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to make me believe that it is the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montréal folks are more attractive unless you&amp;rsquo;re blind and then, it&amp;rsquo;s a tie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to give you some perspective, the subject was brought up by my wife after I had passed myself the same reflection. It can&amp;rsquo;t be anything but the absolute truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Changes Don&amp;rsquo;t Happen in Montréal (anymore), SF Moves with the Wind&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even small things never seem to take forever to get done in Montréal. Not like that here. Plans are approved for a soccer stadium in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/12/02/golden-gate-park-soccer-fields_n_1126206.html&#34;&gt;golden gate park&lt;/a&gt; and plans are for construction to start in a few months to be complete by winter next year. Want a bicycle rack? Just &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sfbike.org/?bikerack&#34;&gt;ask for one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Montreal Trees are Tiny Brocolis, SF Ones Are Giant and Majestic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just look at the pictures (they&amp;rsquo;re online, sorry I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get some here for your convenience). Montréal has colourful maples leaves in fall, that&amp;rsquo;s all. Love trees? Golden Gate park or presidio park is where the magic happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;The Health Care Situation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s do a checklist comparison because we all love those, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doctor office reachable by email: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Online appointment scheduling: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Availability in the following week: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No line-up for lab tests: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Online prescription renewals: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On-time appointments: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Email communication channel between doctor and patient: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montréal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fully loaded doctor calendars months in advance: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Packed waiting rooms full of people to sympathize with: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elaborate congestion system to filter real health problems: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Retro-style one-way communication system: ✓&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is too close. I&amp;rsquo;ll call it a draw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;San Franciscans all Have a Garage and 10 Cars, Montréalers, a bit Less&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People kept telling me I would absolutely need a car when I got here. They would tell me again. And insist. And insist again, telling me I could try living without one but I would give up eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, challenge accepted!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, we can pretty much do all we want without one and &lt;a href=&#34;http://zipcar.com&#34;&gt;zipcar&lt;/a&gt; is there for the luxurious trips like communauto was back in Montréal. However, we are definitely more in an even smaller minority here than we were in Montréal. People have driveways and garages. And they use it. Those garages are filled with cars and that&amp;rsquo;s not just for &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt;. People use their garage and then park another car on the street. It&amp;rsquo;s almost unbelievable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Olds Cars are Still Alive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8083/8301735631_94f6473094_o_d.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        The last sample before I felt very very blasé.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate cars or at least, I dislike them. I still have my driver&amp;rsquo;s license but I&amp;rsquo;m a happy fellow when I see anything that prevents cars from being on the street. However, I love the retro look of cars for their visual attractiveness and how they stand out. You might have seen some instagrams as a proof of that. I stopped doing those though. Not because I don&amp;rsquo;t see any retro cars anymore, it&amp;rsquo;s just the opposite: old pastel blue painted fords, rusty Beatles, buicks, Cadillacs. They survived in California. They&amp;rsquo;re all over the place along with the newer models. Not in junkyards, they&amp;rsquo;re just there around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was blasé after a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;Bicycles are King&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montréal has bixi and bike lanes and flat roads to make it easy for cyclists. SF has steep hills all over and cars are omnipresent. Nonetheless, SF wins the bike culture crown. Those bikes are &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;. Buses wait behind, respectfully. When Muni service routes are shutdown for a week, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfbike.org/?transit&#34;&gt;bike train&lt;/a&gt; route is put in place for commuters. There&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wiggle&#34;&gt;wiggle trail&lt;/a&gt; for people to have a relatively flat route (I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to do it any other way). Apparently people have cars (and many) but they also know it&amp;rsquo;s not very wise to drive it during workdays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bikes are king.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;So who Wins?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could think I regret leaving Montréal and in some ways, I could. Except that I don&amp;rsquo;t really. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice here. And work is great. And there&amp;rsquo;s the ocean, and the golden gate, and all the great tech and the promise of great historical earthquakes. Oh shit shit shit, the earthquakes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey, it&#39;s a Start</title>
      <link>http://heyitsalex.net/hey-its-a-start</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 05:20:03 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <author>Alexandre Normand</author>
      <guid>http://heyitsalex.net/hey-its-a-start</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I may suffer from some condition. Ok well, that&amp;rsquo;s an embarrassing way to start because I really do have a condition as I have type 1 diabetes. But I&amp;rsquo;ve had that since I was a teenager so it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; was I&amp;rsquo;m referring to here. I was actually thinking of this habit of mine of always having some personal project &lt;a href=&#34;http://dawnofbubbles.com/post/6923528541/creation-as-a-fulltime-dad&#34;&gt;on a schedule&lt;/a&gt; and never letting that go. To the point where I get mad for being so near my self-imposed deadline and being stressed out about not being able to deliver. So much so that it seems like all potential of fun is gone, all fun is sucked out of it and it really is making life a misery for me and all people around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that happens only once in a while so it&amp;rsquo;s all good. No problem here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://alexandrenormand.users.sonic.net/heyitsalex.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/crossroads.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        It&amp;#39;s a Road and I Cross it Everyday to Take the Bus. No Joke.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I&amp;rsquo;m really hitching for some new project. You know, something to brag about and put on my software engineer resume in which in no way helps my “career”. I really need this in my life. It guarantees that I have absolutely no time for entertainment while I entertain an adequate amount of sleep deprivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But back to this project discussion. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m actually thinking of mixing things up a bit. I really do think having a restricted scope helps spur creativity but I feel like I can try something more diversified this time around. I may simply be inspired by the relative chaos I&amp;rsquo;m currently living in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, I can&amp;rsquo;t just bring that up and leave it at that: I&amp;rsquo;ve been living since the beginning of my work life in Montreal and it was great. I have a nice cute family with two kids and they all love it there. So what was I to do next? Well, I applied for a job at some remote location and I got it. Then, I had my family give up everything to come with me in San Francisco where we don&amp;rsquo;t know anyone nor speak the language very well. That, my friend (am I moving too quickly saying that?) is the chaos I was taking about. It&amp;rsquo;s not just &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;, obviously, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to ask me for more details if you want me to expand on that topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But back on the project topic again. I actually have a few ideas lined up. What usually happens when I have queue of ideas is&amp;hellip;only one gets executed, if any. In the spirit of getting things done, I&amp;rsquo;m doing &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt;. Notice that &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t an hyperlink. That&amp;rsquo;s because your already on it (okay, I could have many it an anchor link or something but that would have been annoying and not as much fun as me explaining).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yes, I&amp;rsquo;m writing a blog. If you know me, you know I can&amp;rsquo;t really express myself very clearly so that might be a challenge&amp;hellip;or good entertainment for you, the reader. It could go either way. Here is me writing a blog like I&amp;rsquo;ve got something to say that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been said already (or just saying nothing, that&amp;rsquo;s been done too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog about anything, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a Montréaler in California. A dad with almost childish looks with kids that will grow up in another country. A French speaking guy who gets unmasked after speaking half a word of English (or did I say that in French?). A weird stranger in a fast-paced and hard-working tech world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Alex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just Alex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s because Alexandre can&amp;rsquo;t be pronounced correctly in English. That&amp;rsquo;s okay, I can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce anything correctly in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a very climatic opening isn&amp;rsquo;t it? I feel pretty good about this. I think I actually have something good here for a first post. I just have to make sure I&amp;rsquo;m not screwing up the ending (TODO: review that last paragraph before posting).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>