<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>One More Thing To Write About on </title>
    <link>http://www.heyitsalex.net/categories/one-more-thing-to-write-about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in One More Thing To Write About on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 10:00:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.heyitsalex.net/categories/one-more-thing-to-write-about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>New Light on that Blue</title>
      <link>http://www.heyitsalex.net/new-light-on-that-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heyitsalex.net/new-light-on-that-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*What follows is my take on &lt;a href=&#34;http://heyitsalex.net/what-can-happen-in-a-second/&#34;&gt;another&lt;/a&gt; prompt from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Things-Journal-Francisco-Writers-Grotto/dp/1452105448&#34;&gt;642 Things to Write About&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty personal, borderline personal diary. Yeah.
Since this blog is my miscellaneous bucket and I&amp;rsquo;m the editor, I say it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;in&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s ship it. Then, see how it feels.
Do not worry, I&amp;rsquo;m not planning on making regular posts about my feelings, probably.*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So here it is, my take on this prompt:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What a character holding a blue object is thinking about?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There I was, holding a blue pen. I had just lost my train of thought. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly looking at it so much as this was an out of focus blue spot. Not any blue either. It was a blue recalling Québec&amp;rsquo;s national blue. I always felt pretty neutral with that particular hue. I always loved blue but I disliked this particular one, much to my chagrin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today though, this blue is reminiscent of what we&amp;rsquo;ve left behind. We always knew it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be easy to relocate. The nice things about California are indeed &lt;em&gt;nice&lt;/em&gt; but it&amp;rsquo;s not so much like we weren&amp;rsquo;t happy with Montréal. This story isn&amp;rsquo;t one of a quest for the promised land.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/14092047/m%3D900/374628c29b6de4a859eb8bcdb6dbf069&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        There&amp;#39;s that theme of being somewhere else, shot by me in the Golden Gate Park woods.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Some days, we read about cool things that are happening right here, only here. Those days, I feel very fortunate to be here. Other days, we read about some interesting change happening in Montréal and we feel like we&amp;rsquo;re missing out. This is a very typical case of nostalgia versus novelty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that is relatively minor though, in the grand scheme of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything, except one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can do with a slower public transit system.
I can deal with a more complex health care system.
I can accept living in a less lively neighbourhood.
I am however having a real hard time not having friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What friends I hear you thinking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have many. I had to make sacrifices when it became obvious that, as a parent, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to do all I was doing before. Friendship took second place to personal projects and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except that this is oversimplifying. I still had friends. I was seeing some of them almost exclusively at the office but they &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be easy to make new friends. I was anticipating that the English speaking version of me would be struggling to find the words to express nuanced thoughts. It would be more difficult to be &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew it would be a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it harder than I thought it would be? Maybe not. But having anticipated it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any easier to deal with, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also very much neglected the difficulty in coordinating talking with friends in Eastern time. We&amp;rsquo;re living in an always connected world after all, aren’t we? It could be easier if I didn&amp;rsquo;t care so much about my work but I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s what I came here for and I do love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no happy revelation here. No words of wisdom. I didn&amp;rsquo;t make a new friend just today that made everything all better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those things that will incrementally get better over time. I suppose. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure friends are forever but you could say that we forever needs friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I see this blue pen today and it appears in this newly rediscovered grandiose hue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Can Happen in a Second?</title>
      <link>http://www.heyitsalex.net/what-can-happen-in-a-second/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.heyitsalex.net/what-can-happen-in-a-second/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I stumbled upon a book last weekend that caught my attention. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Things-Journal-Francisco-Writers-Grotto/dp/1452105448&#34;&gt;642 Things to Write About&lt;/a&gt;. It contains 642 prompts for things to write about. Simple. With a clearly defined scope, creativity flourishes. If you know me, you know how I like this sort of thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is my take on the first prompt of the book: What Can Happen in a Second? I just wrote without thinking too much about it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Others might follow. Or not. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read the second prompt yet. I will. But I&amp;rsquo;m shipping this one first.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://500px.com/photo/11156255&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ppcdn.500px.org/11156255/cef93067bbb9d90935631a9ddfb7819cf694fd41/4.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        The Patience of a Lonely Boat, shot by me on an old Nikon FE2 with a fantastic Velvia 50. Doesn&amp;#39;t it serve as a good illustration for the slow passage of time?
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s an interesting question and not and an easy one to find answers to. It turns out that in our human world, not much can happen in a second. That may be counterintuitive for some. It just sounds right to our ears to hear that some big thing happened in a split second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s dramatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;That accident occurred in a split second.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From one second to the next, everything went from great to chaos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s interesting about those examples is that they really are not things that happened in a second. If you stop and think about it, in most cases, an accident had been in gestation for several seconds, minutes, hours, days. Sensationalism and big drama makes us report it otherwise. That, however, can be a rant for some other day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me share this personal story. A story you might know about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was this moment last year when my life took a turn. I had received an invitation for a job recruitment event in Montreal for a position on the United States West Coast. I was not really considering relocating but my wife said: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Why not?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Indeed, why not? At that moment, I started steering towards that new path. The horizon opened. You could argue that this change occurred at that second. I disagree. I think I had been contemplating the idea for some time. This idea was far-fetched, unrealistic. But that moment when that question triggered important and new answers was important not in itself, but as a tipping point in a series of events, experiences, reflections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say that not much happens in a second, that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m referring to. There&amp;rsquo;s that decisive moment that breaks the &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; and we&amp;rsquo;re tempted to think it all happened &lt;em&gt;right then&lt;/em&gt; but I believe the reality is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure we pass by such moments everyday because we&amp;rsquo;re not in the right mindset (which is quite alright too). As much as big drama seems to feed on split seconds twists, it&amp;rsquo;s often all the little moments that make a big one possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what can happen in one second? Millions of computations? Several frames in a video? Thousands of tweets? Yes, yes, yes and yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when we’re talking about stories, there’s always more hidden behind that instant of drama.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>