<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>calvinball project on Hey, it&#39;s Alex!</title>
    <link>https://heyitsalex.net/categories/calvinball-project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in calvinball project on Hey, it&#39;s Alex!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 05:58:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/calvinball-project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Juxtapose</title>
      <link>https://heyitsalex.net/juxtapose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 05:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heyitsalex.net/juxtapose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I came across some stunning &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/a/wxBBm#0&#34;&gt;compositing work&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://realcalvinandhobbes.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;Michael Den Beste&lt;/a&gt;. The project juxtaposes drawings of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calvin_and_Hobbes&#34;&gt;Calvin and Hobbes&lt;/a&gt; with fitting nature photographs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By themselves, the photos would be pretty good albeit lacking a distinguishing element. With Calvin and Hobbes, the scene comes alive. The drawings bring a touch of imagination in an otherwise very real scene. I felt as if the world was being filled with mystical creatures from storybooks. It&#39;s breaking the monotony of a thousand pretty pictures while celebrating of the beauty of nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can tell I felt inspired by that work. I also happen to take random unpublished pictures suited for such compositing work: &lt;em&gt;wallpaper-nice&lt;/em&gt; caliber but nothing crazy unique. I also happen to draw things. Or, I try to. Here is my first attempt at this type of composite art. It&#39;s an old pouring rain picture that I augmented with my drawing of a snail. I have much better photos in reserve for this type of work but this one seemed to be fitting with my character so I&#39;m going with that. Uncharacteristically for me, this won&#39;t be a scheduled project. But, I&#39;ll make more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8234/8508412905_e34d5b1429_b.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        This is it.
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
